<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Investing 102 Archives - DiversyFund</title>
	<atom:link href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/category/investing-102/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/category/investing-102/</link>
	<description>Real Estate Investing Platform</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 18:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Impact of AI on Alternative Investments</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/10/20/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 18:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AI, or Artificial Intelligence, has been a focal point in many news stories across countless industries, as the rise of chatbots and AI software have begun changing the way many...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/10/20/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments/">The Impact of AI on Alternative Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>AI, or Artificial Intelligence, has been a focal point in many news stories across countless industries, as the rise of chatbots and AI software have begun changing the way many companies do business. The world of finance is no exception, and AI may soon play a key role in the way investors plan their financial strategies. The use of AI with respect to alternative investments is particularly interesting, so we thought we’d examine the impact the technology is already having on this sector of the markets/</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI and Asset Management</h2>



<p>In years past, primarily only the wealthy could afford to have their alternative assets managed by an expert. The cost of this type of wealth management service was prohibitive, and everyday investors might not have had the sophistication to direct their own investments independently. Today, AI can be used to provide advice and planning services with limited human supervision, although it is always a good idea for investors to keep an eye on their accounts and consult with a financial expert to review their investment strategies. AI for asset management essentially levels the playing field for investors looking to expand their portfolios beyond traditional stocks and bonds, creating a paradigm shift and making more investment options accessible to the masses. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26297" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate Investing and AI</h2>



<p>Investing in real estate takes a substantial amount of research, as investors must monitor market trends as a whole, including economic indicators, trends in rent rates and vacancies, and property value trends. This can be labor-intensive, which can also make investing less accessible for those who aren’t full-time real estate investors. AI can minimize the amount of work needed by analyzing data and trends, providing better information investors can use to select their next real estate asset. Both individual investors and those looking at private market real estate funds can benefit from AI technology, but it’s important to remember that a human touch is still needed. An asset manager who can fact-check the data and analyze more nuanced information the artificial intelligence gathers may still be needed.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bringing AI into Private Market Assets</h2>



<p>AI technology’s use isn’t limited to basic asset management and real estate investing. Private market assets, such as <a href="https://www.techopedia.com/the-role-of-ai-in-venture-capital-evolution-or-replacement">venture capital</a>, can also reap the rewards of this new technology. Data analysis and predictive analysis are used to determine the potential future success of an investment, which reduces the amount of time needed to research before a decision on investing is made. For the world of venture capital, that saved time can mean the difference between getting in on the ground floor of a startup and missing the opportunity. While AI is used to help predict the success or failure of an investment, it’s important to note that the technology isn’t foolproof. Investors still run the same risks as they would if human data analysis was used.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Ethics of AI and Alternative Investments</h2>



<p>There has been much debate about the overall ethics of using AI, from whether or not the entertainment industry should use it to generate scripts and synthetic performers to the potential for data breaches when using the technology to gather information. In the world of finance, there are several key concerns investors should consider before deploying artificial intelligence as part of a portfolio optimization strategy:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.finastra.com/sites/default/files/documents/2021/03/market-insight_algorithmic-bias-financial-services.pdf"><strong>Algorithmic biases</strong></a>: Biases in data being analyzed, as well as information gathered by AI while examining the data, can lead to flaws in the results. In some cases, it can even lead to discrimination. For example, algorithmic biases could result in financing for an investment being denied based on an individual’s age, race, or gender.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Data privacy and security</strong>: Individuals tend to closely guard their financial information, and for good reason. You want to make sure your data and your accounts are secure. Sharing information with AI software to analyze your portfolio and financial situation could leave you vulnerable to data breaches and the potential loss of privacy.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Loss of Human Oversight</strong>: Investors who are used to working with an asset manager or financial advisor may have a difficult time accepting the idea that a machine will be handling their finances, and the lack of human oversight can leave accounts vulnerable to potentially bad advice if there is no oversight. AI replacing humans in key roles may also be an ethical concern for some, as the wide scale loss of jobs can have a negative impact on the economy and investment markets.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26298" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>AI technology is still new, and financial institutions are just learning how to best use this tool to help inform decisions about investments. Asset managers can add AI to their analyses without solely relying on it to make decisions, and the technology can have some great advantages for those looking to invest in private market real estate, venture capital, and other alternative assets. Of course, it’s always best to consult with your financial expert before making any money moves, and that includes having a discussion before using AI to help plan your financial strategy. To learn more about DIversyFund’s alternative investment opportunities and how they can fit into your financial goals, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/10/20/the-impact-of-ai-on-alternative-investments/">The Impact of AI on Alternative Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Balancing Act: Traditional vs. Alternative Assets in Your Portfolio</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/16/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 22:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative assets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balanced portfolio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Having a diverse, balanced portfolio is key for investors, and this means balancing traditional and alternative assets to have a healthy mix of investments. While having stocks and bonds can...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/16/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio/">Balancing Act: Traditional vs. Alternative Assets in Your Portfolio</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Having a diverse, balanced portfolio is key for investors, and this means balancing traditional and alternative assets to have a healthy mix of investments. While having stocks and bonds can be good options for any portfolio, alternative assets provide key benefits, such as hedging against inflation. Investors like you can mitigate risk and begin building long-term wealth with strategic asset allocation. Let’s take a closer look at alternative investments, including real estate, to see how they integrate into a balanced portfolio.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Are Alternative Assets?</h2>



<p><a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/maximizing-returns-with-alternative-investments-a-guide-for-accredited-investors/">Alternative investments</a> are those that fall outside of conventional categories, some of which may be subject to fewer SEC regulations. They may carry varying levels of risk compared to their traditional counterparts, but this can also mean greater rewards too. Alternative assets include everything from multifamily real estate to hedge funds. Commodities, such as silver and gold, are also considered alternative investments. You can grow and diversify your portfolio with a mix of these different assets, or you can rely on just one or two to begin building wealth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26229" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Role of Multifamily Real Estate Assets</h2>



<p>While some alternative assets are still subject to market volatility, multifamily real estate provides a simple way to hedge against the markets and inflation. Real estate can generate reliable monthly cash flow, and can appreciate over time for profitable sales. The demand for rental housing is a constant, and demand has even grown in recent years due to the shortage of affordable single-family homes. REITs and single-asset offerings even give investors ways to pool their money together to purchase properties and share both the risks and returns of owning property.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Risk versus Return</h2>



<p>All investors need to weigh the risks of alternative assets against their potential returns. Commodities are traded in spot markets or derivative markets and have the potential to be very volatile, sometimes even more than stocks. The return can be high for significant commodities investments, but they come with great risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some investors choose to put their money into physical, more tangible assets, such as art or collectibles. These assets aren’t traded daily like stocks and bonds, which may lead to more stable values. However, investing in physical assets does present some challenges, such as limited liquidity and the need for speculation on future value. Investors looking for these types of assets should have a passion for the items they invest in, as they may end up owning the goods for a number of years before being able to sell.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://diversyfund.com/why-real-estate/">Multifamily real estate</a> is an option for investors who are looking to diversify their portfolios with assets that meet a need and provide a service to the public. Apartment buildings or complexes can provide stable cash flow despite market downturns, as the need for housing is a constant. This type of investment can also work for investors who are risk-averse and may not feel comfortable with commodities or other similar assets.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26230" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Asset Allocation Models</h2>



<p>Asset allocation is key for creating a healthy, diverse portfolio. They help investors gain a better understanding of the potential returns they can expect to see from their portfolios. While these models can be quite complex, they can be broken down into three basic types of portfolios, growth, balanced, and income. Each one requires a different mix of traditional and alternative assets. The goal of each portfolio is different, but you can create multiple portfolios with different financial goals. An income portfolio might be used to provide cash flow you want access to right now, while a growth portfolio can be used to help plan for your future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Allocating assets may include stocks and bonds, but adding real estate to any of your asset allocation models can help generate income and build long-term wealth. Relying too heavily on stocks, even for an income portfolio, can leave investors subject to potential market volatility. Real estate may help some investors strike the right balance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Creating your own personal balanced investment strategy depends on your own financial needs and goals, as well as your personal risk tolerance. As always, you should discuss your financial situation with a professional before making any money moves. You’ll want to keep both traditional and alternative assets in mind as you weigh your options.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/16/balancing-act-traditional-vs-alternative-assets-in-your-portfolio/">Balancing Act: Traditional vs. Alternative Assets in Your Portfolio</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going Green: Sustainable Multifamily Investing Makes Dollars and Sense</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/30/sustainable-multifamily-investing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 22:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainable Investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Going green isn’t just a trendy phrase real estate developers and investors use; sustainable multifamily investing offers benefits for tenants, owners, and the environment. Sustainability can be applied in many...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/30/sustainable-multifamily-investing/">Going Green: Sustainable Multifamily Investing Makes Dollars and Sense</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Going green isn’t just a trendy phrase real estate developers and investors use; sustainable multifamily investing offers benefits for tenants, owners, and the environment. Sustainability can be applied in many ways, and the right executions can reduce operating costs, increase property value, and yield greater returns. Let’s take a closer look at these practices and how well they can work.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Green Certifications</h2>



<p>Green certifications can provide real estate investors with a host of savings. You may have already heard of LEED certification, which is a commonly used and recognized green building rating system. LEED stands for Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design, and the certifications are given to both new construction buildings and those sustainable multifamily assets that have undergone recent green renovations. Advertising your building’s LEED certification status can potentially command higher rents and lower turnover. A recent study showed <a href="https://www.mrisoftware.com/blog/multifamily-data-research-renters-want-sustainability/">61% percent</a> of respondents were willing to pay more to live in an eco-friendly apartment, and research compiled by the <a href="https://www.aia.org/pages/6409388-roi-increasing-asset-values">American Institute of Architects</a> shows the following stats: </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26173" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Financial institutions like Freddie Mac offer <a href="https://mf.freddiemac.com/product/green-advantage">discounted loan pricing</a> to multifamily investors who meet certain certification requirements, and the U.S. Department of Energy provides a range of tax incentives for buildings that have met specific standards. For example, buildings meeting a predetermined benchmark for energy savings can take a <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/buildings/tax-incentives-energy-efficiency-upgrades-commercial-buildings">tax deduction</a> of up to $1.80 per square foot or partial deductions of up to $0.60 per square foot. Though these savings may seem nominal at first, they can truly add up for large properties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>State and local municipalities may also have their own programs for grants, tax incentives, and other financial benefits. In essence, going green can actually pay when done correctly. Investors should also look into benefits for other green building investments. New financial incentives are being added all the time, so it’s a good idea for investors to look for additional programs, even if their buildings are already green-certified.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Green Building Investments</h2>



<p>Owners and investors of multifamily real estate can implement a wide range of green building investments to realize cost and tax savings for their properties. Green building materials, such as reclaimed wood, recycled plastic, and bamboo, can be used for renovations or new builds. Switching to LED lighting and installing energy-saving windows are simple upgrades that can have a big impact. Other options for green building investments might include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Install low-flow plumbing fixtures</li>



<li>Switch to zero-VOC paints</li>



<li>Replace old appliances with more efficient ENERGY STAR-rated appliances</li>



<li>Install smart thermostats</li>



<li>Upgrade to solar panels</li>



<li>Set up compost and recycling stations outside of your buildings</li>
</ul>



<p>Energy-saving strategies for multifamily real estate can take many forms, but ultimately investors will need to balance the cost of upgrades with the potential benefits to determine which options make the most sense for their properties. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26175" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Green Spaces and Amenities</h2>



<p>Integrating green spaces into sustainable multifamily apartment buildings and complexes can increase curb appeal and create more of a neighborhood atmosphere, but they also provide additional benefits for the environment. Vegetation, whether it takes the form of grass and trees or a community garden, acts as a natural air filtration system, helping <a href="https://www.un.org/en/chronicle/article/green-spaces-invaluable-resource-delivering-sustainable-urban-health">reduce air pollution and carbon emissions</a>. Plants and flowers can also have a calming effect, which can impact the overall quality of living for tenants. With simple and strategic landscaping additions for multifamily assets, real estate investors can leverage sustainability to help improve the lives of tenants, benefit the environment, and boost the value of a property.</p>



<p>You can also make your multifamily real estate property more desirable by adding any number of green amenities as part of your <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management/">property management strategy</a>. Adding bike racks and a bike path on the property can be a smart move for properties in or near a city center, and electric vehicle charging stations in your parking lot help your property stand out. Adding a community garden space can benefit the environment and your renters. All these amenities make great selling points as you advertise your property to future tenants.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-04-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26176" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-04-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-04-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-04-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-04-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/going-green-sustainable-multifamily-investing-makes-dollars-and-sense-04.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sustainable Multifamily Investing and What it Means for You</h2>



<p>The need to help repair and maintain the environment is clear, and sustainable investing or environmental impact investing can make you feel good about the ways you choose to build wealth. By choosing green upgrades for existing investments and looking for properties that already use some of these practices, your money goes toward benefiting the environment and creating a better life for tenants.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/30/sustainable-multifamily-investing/">Going Green: Sustainable Multifamily Investing Makes Dollars and Sense</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evaluating Multifamily Investments From Risk Assessment to Exit Strategy</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/12/evaluating-multifamily-investments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 22:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investing terms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Multifamily real estate can be a great option for diversifying an investment portfolio, but evaluating properties for their potential is essential. There are many criteria you can use to vet...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/12/evaluating-multifamily-investments/">Evaluating Multifamily Investments From Risk Assessment to Exit Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Multifamily real estate can be a great option for diversifying an investment portfolio, but evaluating properties for their potential is essential. There are many criteria you can use to vet possible investment properties, and we’ll take a closer look at some of the most important ones to help you prepare for becoming a real estate investor.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Risk Assessment</h2>



<p>A risk assessment, or risk analysis, takes different factors into account to help you determine how financially sound a property might be. An assessment might look at market risk, operational risk, and financial risk factors, giving you an indication of the assets potential for loss. High vacancy rates and tenant turnover, the need for extensive repairs, and a history of poor cash flow are all risks that might indicate a property will not perform for you. Individual investors can hire an outside company to perform a risk assessment for a property to take some of the task out of evaluating multifamily investments, but single-asset real estate investment funds for accredited investors and REITs for non-accredited investors take care of risk assessments for each property so you don’t have to.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NOI (Net Operating Income)</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/n/noi.asp">NOI</a> or Net Operating Income lets you analyze a property’s profitability. The equation for this metric is to subtract the operating expenses from the total revenue generated, resulting in the net income. It’s important to remember that this is a pre-tax number that does not take the principle and interest from any loans into account, and it also doesn’t consider capital expenses, amortization, or depreciation. The higher the NOI, the better the potential for a property as an investment. Of course, this isn’t the only metric you’ll be looking at as you decide which multifamily real estate asset to invest in.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26094" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cap Rates</h2>



<p>Once you’ve determined the NOI for a property, you can then begin to look at <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/cap-rates-explained/?utm_source=inbound%20content%20&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-5-12">cap rates</a>, otherwise known as capitalization rates. The cap rate gives you better insight into a property’s rate of return. Cap rates for property can be determined by dividing the NOI by the asset’s current market value. However, some analysts will divide the NOI by an asset’s purchase price. Current market value may be a better option, as the second option doesn’t take changes in the real estate market into account. You can use the cap rate to help determine how long it will take to recover your initial investment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gross Rent Multiplier</h2>



<p>Another metric to use when evaluating multifamily real estate investments is the <a href="https://www.rocketmortgage.com/learn/gross-rent-multiplier">GRM</a>, or Gross Rent Multiplier. The GRM is the ratio of the price of a property to its annual rental income, not including any expenses. Looking at the GRM for a single property might not always provide you with a lot of information, but comparing GRMs for several multifamily properties can help you narrow down your options so you can make a more informed investment decision. There’s no one standard for what constitutes a good GRM, as the ideal number will vary from one market to the next. A higher GRM in an affluent area might be better than a lower GRM in a middle-class community, so it’s important to compare properties that are similar.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Investment Horizon</h2>



<p>The investment horizon is a factor that relies on your investment needs. You’ll want to determine if you’re looking for a long-term cash flow or short-term investment. A realistic timetable for your investment will help you determine which type of property is right for you. Some investors may want to sell, fix, and flip for a short-term strategy, while others may want to hold onto a multifamily asset for its revenue-generating potential. Some properties are better suited to short-term strategies while others are ideal for building long-term wealth. You can use the metrics already discussed in this blog to evaluate each asset to see how it fits with your investment horizon.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Exit Strategy</h2>



<p>Your exit strategy is your plan for selling the property eventually, and it will depend on your investment horizon. Some individual investors may not want an exit strategy at all, and will instead use the property as a source of income for the long-haul. However, if you do want to sell at some point, having a clearly defined strategy can help you maximize your profits. You may want to set certain parameters for market performance so you’re ready to sell when the conditions are right. A timetable for your investment can also help you determine how much money you’re willing to put into the property. A long-term investment means performing renovations and repairs to maintain the property and boost your cash flow as much as possible, while a short-term strategy might rely on improving the asset enough to garner a higher selling price and nothing more.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26095" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/how-to-evaluate-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Evaluating multifamily real estate investments can be a complex undertaking, but there are options available to make it easier. <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/?utm_source=inbound%20content%20&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-5-12">DiversyFund’s REITs and Premier Offerings</a> consist of carefully vetted multifamily assets, and our team of experts do all the research to determine the risks, NOI, cap rates, and GRM for you. They are long-term investment strategies, so you don’t even have to worry about determining your investment horizon or exit strategy. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/12/evaluating-multifamily-investments/">Evaluating Multifamily Investments From Risk Assessment to Exit Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Risk Management: Overcoming Common Challenges in Multifamily Real Estate Investing</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/05/risk-management-overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 20:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative assets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Multifamily real estate investing, like all forms of investing, comes with its own set of unique challenges, and that&#8217;s where risk management comes in. Savvy investors will know how to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/05/risk-management-overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing/">Risk Management: Overcoming Common Challenges in Multifamily Real Estate Investing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Multifamily real estate investing, like all forms of investing, comes with its own set of unique challenges, and that&#8217;s where risk management comes in. Savvy investors will know how to identify and overcome some of these challenges to give their portfolios the best chances for successful growth. Analyzing, managing, and mitigating risk are essential, and we’ll dive in to better understand these concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Risk</h2>



<p>Risk is the potential for loss or negative performance for an investment asset. For multifamily real estate properties, risk might refer to high rates of tenant turnover, low market rates for rent, or high supply and low demand for housing. Informed investors take potential risk into account when making financial decisions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Risk Analysis</h2>



<p>Identifying potential risks provides investors with a roadmap to overcoming obstacles, and there are several different types to look for when performing <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/r/risk-analysis.asp#:~:text=Risk%20analysis%20is%20the%20process,mitigate%20or%20eliminate%20that%20risk.">risk analysis</a>, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>Market Risk: The conditions of any given real estate market, including vacancy rates, population growth, current housing supply, and the overall demand for housing.</li>



<li>Operational Risk: Risks associated with managing a property, costs of repairs and renovations, tenant turnover, and other related factors.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Financial Risk: Economic factors, such as properties that carry too much debt or have less-than-ideal cash flow.</li>
</ul>



<p>There are, of course, other types of risks, and some risks can fall into multiple categories. However, these three basic types can provide valuable information when conducting an analysis. These factors can all be measured in metrics known as Key Risk Indicators (KRIs). KRIs can show the potential exposure of a multifamily real estate asset, giving investors the insight needed when deciding to buy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26087" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Risk Management in Real Estate</h2>



<p>Investors can manage risk by making smart decisions about which properties to add to their portfolio. Watching market trends and performing a risk analysis on an asset before purchasing can help predict potential cash flow and avoid assets that might carry too much risk to be lucrative. For example,  Property A has a high vacancy rate and needs extensive repairs. Property B in the same market with a low vacancy rate and minimal repair needs. While Property A may be less expensive to purchase, it carries greater risk. Managing risk might involve spending more on the second asset to hedge against potential losses.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Mitigating Risk in Real Estate</h2>



<p>Sometimes it makes more financial sense to purchase a multifamily property that’s a bit riskier. Investors will mitigate risk in this scenario to help prevent losses and foster growth, creating an action plan to address all concerns. If we take the example from above, Property B may carry lower risk, but Property A might be closer to local schools, parks, and public transit. With the right risk mitigation, it’s possible that Property B could be the better investment option. Mitigating risk in this situation might involve addressing repair concerns, screening potential new tenants, and creating a marketing strategy to attract new residents. By addressing and planning for these risks, it’s possible to increase the potential cash flow for the asset and overcome challenges.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26088" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>Effective risk management isn’t always easy, but investors have options to help. REITs allow investors to put their money in a portfolio of multifamily real estate assets, each of which is analyzed for risk and potential profitability. A diverse real estate portfolio can help hedge against losses. Investors can also pool their money with others to invest in a single real estate asset so no one investor assumes all the risk on their own. <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/?utm_source=inbound%20content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog%20post-5-5">DiversyFund</a> offers options for accredited and non-accredited investors through its single-asset Premier Offerings and Growth Funds.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/05/risk-management-overcoming-common-challenges-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing/">Risk Management: Overcoming Common Challenges in Multifamily Real Estate Investing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maximizing Returns with Alternative Investments: A Guide for Accredited Investors</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/07/maximizing-returns-with-alternative-investments-a-guide-for-accredited-investors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 20:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accredited]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accredited Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commodities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hedge Funds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Accredited investors are fortunate to have many different options available to them, and alternative investments can provide lucrative ways to diversify a portfolio alongside maximizing returns. If you’re an accredited...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/07/maximizing-returns-with-alternative-investments-a-guide-for-accredited-investors/">Maximizing Returns with Alternative Investments: A Guide for Accredited Investors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Accredited investors are fortunate to have many different options available to them, and alternative investments can provide lucrative ways to diversify a portfolio alongside maximizing returns. If you’re an accredited investor and are looking for ways to build growth outside of traditional stocks and bonds, we’ve compiled a list of ideas to inspire your investment strategy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate for Accredited Investors</h2>



<p>Accredited investors are eligible to participate in a number of different real estate investments not open to the general public. Each one has different benefits for investors, so it’s easy to find one that might align with your wealth-building goals. We’ll go over three options briefly, but remember there are many ways to invest in real estate.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26060" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/real-estate-investing/basics/real-estate-syndication/">Real estate syndications</a>, for example, allow accredited investors to pool their money together to purchase a single asset. Through this process, they can invest in a multimillion-dollar property, such as an apartment complex, shopping mall, or industrial warehouse, without shouldering the entire cost and risk. Investors typically select the manager they want to work with to act as the fiduciary, finding the property for investment and providing due diligence throughout the process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An alternative to real estate syndications is real estate crowdfunding, which also allows accredited investors to pool money for the purchase of a single asset (though some crowdfunding options are also open to non-accredited investors too). However, with crowdfunding, investors are more able to select the asset they wish to invest in. The sponsor for the purchase is already selected, so individuals have the freedom to choose how they want their money invested instead of relying on the sponsor to make the right call. </p>



<p><br>Investors wanting to get into the real estate game without investing in a single asset can opt for <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/110215/how-do-real-estate-hedge-funds-work.asp">real estate hedge funds</a>. These funds typically purchase stock in publicly-traded REITs and may also purchase real estate assets, creating their own investment portfolios. </p>



<p>Accredited investors focused on maximizing returns can also invest in funds under Rule 506 of Regulation D under the JOBS Act. You can learn more about this Rule — and its subcategories — here. Many of these funds focus on opportunistic real estate investments, specifically those that are priced below market value.<br><br><a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-4-7-23">DiversyFund Premier Offerings</a> are focused on maximizing potential returns through both single-asset direct investment and opportunistic funds, specifically targeting distressed assets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Commodities</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26061" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/commodity.asp">Commodities</a>, such as gold and silver, have a history of helping people diversify their portfolios with alternative investments. Accredited investors can go beyond simply purchasing gold bullion or buying stock in a company dealing with commodities. Commodity hedge funds put the concept on a larger scale, investing directly or indirectly in raw materials or agricultural products. For example, a hedge fund might invest in crude oil, cattle, or platinum. There are several different types of commodity funds: indexes, futures, or direct positions. As with any investment, commodities hedge funds carry risk, but they tend to invest in materials and products that have consistent demand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hedge Funds</h2>



<p>We’ve already covered two types of specific hedge funds, but it’s important to note there are many types of funds available to accredited investors. Global, distressed debt, emerging markets, and event-driven hedge funds are just some choices investors can choose. The level of complexity for hedge funds can be considerable, which is why they are only open to accredited investors. For example, <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/e/eventdriven.asp">event-driven</a> hedge funds seek to benefit from bankruptcies, hostile takeovers, and mergers. Emerging market funds invest heavily in assets from countries with emerging economies, essentially making a bet on the success of those nations. These complicated funds require a unique level of understanding, which is why they are typically open only to accredited individuals. However, hedge funds do give investors a way to target a specific industry or market, so you can find an option that fits with your area of expertise. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-04-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26062" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-04-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-04-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-04-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-04-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/alternative-investment-options-for-accredited-investors-04.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><br>Accredited investors have the luxury of having access to a vast number of opportunities for portfolio diversification. Hedge funds can be lucrative, though they also may be subject to market volatility. Commodities may provide a more conservative choice when compared to event-driven hedge funds, and real estate provides a unique option to hedge against market volatility. No matter how you choose to leverage your status as an accredited investor, it’s important to discuss any money moves with your financial expert first. To learn more about DiversyFund’s opportunities for accredited investors, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-4-7-23">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/07/maximizing-returns-with-alternative-investments-a-guide-for-accredited-investors/">Maximizing Returns with Alternative Investments: A Guide for Accredited Investors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growing Wealth: Reg A Offerings vs. Reg D Offerings</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/27/growing-wealth-reg-a-offerings-vs-reg-d-offerings/</link>
					<comments>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/27/growing-wealth-reg-a-offerings-vs-reg-d-offerings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 22:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reg A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reg D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rule 504]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rule 506]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC regulations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=25952</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Understanding the Securities and Exchange Commision (SEC) regulations can help investors choose the right products when it comes to growing wealth. Two key regulations you may need to know are...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/27/growing-wealth-reg-a-offerings-vs-reg-d-offerings/">Growing Wealth: Reg A Offerings vs. Reg D Offerings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Understanding the Securities and Exchange Commision (SEC) regulations can help investors choose the right products when it comes to growing wealth. Two key regulations you may need to know are Reg A and Reg D. Both are regulations that deal with exemptions from SEC requirements, but they both work differently. If you haven’t heard of either term, or if you simply don’t know how each of these regulations work, use the following guide to gain a better understanding of SEC Reg A and&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reg D.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is SEC Reg A?</h2>



<p>SEC Reg A is an exemption from registration requirements for a public offering of securities. The benefit of filing under this regulation is less stringent documentation requirements, which make it easier to create a public offering. This regulation also makes it possible for non-accredited investors to take advantage of offerings they might not otherwise have access to. There are two tiers to SEC Reg A; Tier 1 and Tier 2, and they each have their own set of requirements.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Tier 1</h3>



<p>Under Tier 1, the company issuing a public offering can raise up to $20 million in a 12-month period. Of that $20 million, <a href="https://www.investor.gov/introduction-investing/investing-basics/glossary/regulation">no more than $6 million</a> can be raised on behalf of selling securityholders that are affiliates of the issuer. While companies using Reg A Tier 1 do not have ongoing reporting requirements, they are responsible for filing their offerings. They must go through the process of having their filings qualified by state securities regulators in every state they plan to do business. Investors in Tier 1 offerings do not need to be accredited, so you can invest in these assets without meeting stringent wealth requirements. SEC Reg A Tier 1 offerings are typically better suited for smaller companies or those doing primarily local business, as the maximum raise is significantly lower than that of Tier 2.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="563" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_02-1024x563.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-25954" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_02-1024x563.jpg 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_02-300x165.jpg 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_02-768x422.jpg 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_02.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Tier 2</h3>



<p>With Tier 2, companies can raise a maximum of $75 million in a 12-month period. As with Tier 1, there is a limit on how much can be raised on behalf of security holders that are affiliates of the issuers. Previous to the 2015 JOBS Act, the limit was $50 million, and this change has benefited larger companies looking to create a public offering. You may see some investments referred to as Reg A+, which refers to a Reg A Tier 2 investment that qualifies under the changes made to the SEC regulations under the JOBS Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unlike Tier 1, Tier 2 offerings do not need to be registered with or qualified by state securities regulators, which can further streamline the process of creating a public offering. Tier 2 does accept non-accredited investors, but there is a limit on how much you can invest without being accredited.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is SEC Reg D?</h2>



<p>Simply put, SEC Reg D is an exemption from registration requirements for private companies or entrepreneurs. It’s a smart tool for smaller companies that can’t handle the expense of a public offering but still want to raise capital and open their businesses to investors. While Reg A has its two-tiered system, Reg D comprises two rules: Rule 504 and Rule 506.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rule 504</h3>



<p><a href="https://www.investor.gov/introduction-investing/investing-basics/glossary/rule-504-regulation-d">Rule 504</a> limits companies to offering and selling up to $10 million in securities in a 12-month period. There are some exceptions, but investors will typically receive a “restricted security.” This means the security can’t be sold for between 6 months and 1 year without registering them with the SEC. The company must file a Form D to create an offering under Rule 504, and it must provide accurate information to investors to help prevent them from violating anti-fraud provisions (such as selling their securities early without registering them with the SEC). General solicitation is not permitted under Rule 504, so companies can’t advertise their offerings to the public. Under Rule 504, investors do not need to be accredited to take advantage of an offering.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rule 506</h3>



<p>There are two subcategories of <a href="https://www.investor.gov/introduction-investing/investing-basics/glossary/rule-506-regulation-d">Rule 506</a>, which are 506(b) and 506(c). Like Rule 504, investments under rule 506 are restricted securities and can’t be sold for 6 months to 1 year from their initial purchase without registering them. Both subcategories permit unlimited contributions, but there are key differences that make each one unique.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under Rule 506(b), companies are limited to just 35 non-accredited investors, and general solicitation to the public is prohibited. There is no limit to the number of accredited investors allowed under 506(b). Non-accredited investors must be considered sophisticated, with enough financial knowledge to understand the risks and potential outcome of their investment. They must be provided with disclosure documentation, and any documents provided to accredited investors must be shared with non-accredited investors as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>With Rule 506(c), all investors must be accredited, without exception. Companies are expected to take all reasonable steps to ensure the accredited status of its investors through examining tax documents and other financial statements. Unlike the other types of exemptions we’ve already discussed, Rule 506(C) does allow for general solicitation. This means companies can advertise their offerings as part of their efforts to raise capital. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="526" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_03-1024x526.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-25955" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_03-1024x526.jpg 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_03-300x154.jpg 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_03-768x394.jpg 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_differences_between_reg_a_offerings_and_reg_d_offerings_03.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Growing Wealth: Comparing Reg A and Reg D</h2>



<p>SEC Reg A is aimed at public offerings, while Reg D is geared toward private offerings. Both regulations make it easier for companies to raise the capital they need while still providing some oversight and potential protection for investors. There are specific filing requirements for both, and companies are required to provide financial disclosures to investors to help them stay informed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Non-accredited investors can take advantage of several of the regulation subcategories, though there are considerable restrictions under Reg D. Whether you’re accredited or not, a certain level of sophistication is required to fully understand the risks and rewards of both public and private offerings. As with any investment, it’s important to discuss your options with a financial advisor before making any changes to your portfolio. DiversyFund has recently introduced our Premier Offerings for accredited investors, and you can read more about them <a href="https://diversyfund.com/premier-offerings/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/27/growing-wealth-reg-a-offerings-vs-reg-d-offerings/">Growing Wealth: Reg A Offerings vs. Reg D Offerings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/27/growing-wealth-reg-a-offerings-vs-reg-d-offerings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Fintech Trends for Investors to Watch</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/07/three-fintech-trends-for-investors-to-watch/</link>
					<comments>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/07/three-fintech-trends-for-investors-to-watch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking as a Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[REITs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=25827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The fintech industry is home to exciting innovations, and investors can learn a lot from watching up-and-coming fintech trends. Keeping an eye on new trends may help inform your investing...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/07/three-fintech-trends-for-investors-to-watch/">Three Fintech Trends for Investors to Watch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The fintech industry is home to exciting innovations, and investors can learn a lot from watching up-and-coming fintech trends. Keeping an eye on new trends may help inform your investing choices and help you build long-term wealth. Here are just some of the fintech happenings to keep on your radar as you look for new investment opportunities in 2023.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Banking as a Service</h2>



<p><a href="https://plaid.com/resources/fintech/what-is-embedded-finance/">Banking as a Service</a>, also referred to as embedded finance offerings, give consumers access to a wide range of financial services outside of standard checking and savings accounts. You may already be familiar with some companies that have implemented Banking as a Service, such as PayPal and Venmo, but even companies that don’t operate in the fintech world have begun using this fintech trend.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>So what is Banking as a Service? It’s a system that allows companies that aren’t banks to roll out unique financial products. Examples of this might include retailers that offer pay-in-four services at checkout or travel booking companies with built-in financing options to pay for vacation packages. In both cases, we see non-banks providing customers with options traditionally offered by banks. In essence, Banking as a Service brings fintech functionality to all sectors of business. This fintech trend is projected to be worth as much as <a href="https://www.alliedmarketresearch.com/banking-as-a-service-market-A14258">$11.34 billion</a> by the year 2030 as the trend grows over the next decade.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="549" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-02-1024x549.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25831" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-02-1024x549.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-02-300x161.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-02-768x412.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-02.png 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crypto-Linked Cards</h2>



<p>As crypto currency and blockchains become more accepted in the financial world, the fintech industry has paved the way in providing access to crypto-linked cards and payment services. Visa reported <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/28/visa-says-crypto-linked-card-usage-hit-2point5-billion-in-its-first-quarter.html">$2.5 billion</a> in payments made via its crypto-based credit card in the first quarter of 2022 alone. The benefit of these cards for consumers is the ability to withdraw cash from ATMs and make payments to retailers without having to convert their cryptocurrency first. <a href="https://money.usnews.com/credit-cards/articles/is-a-bitcoin-credit-card-right-for-you">Crypto debit and credit cards</a> also offer some of the rewards you might already have with your traditional banking and credit card accounts, such as loyalty rewards and points.&nbsp;<br>This is all potentially good news for individuals investing in both cryptocurrency and the banks operating the crypto cards, though it is important to note the volatility of the crypto markets, especially in light of recent developments within that market. Both account balances and reward values may fluctuate wildly, depending on the crypto markets, and money held in crypto accounts <a href="https://www.fdic.gov/news/fact-sheets/crypto-fact-sheet-7-28-22.pdf">is not FDIC-insured</a> in the same way U.S. currency is.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Artificial Intelligence</h2>



<p>AI is also used in real estate to help monitor and predict market trends, analyze data, and provide insight into potential investments. REITs can take advantage of AI to identify market trends and inform their decisions when adding assets to a portfolio.  Individuals looking to buy a home can use AI to find a mortgage at their ideal rates, and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/17/what-artificial-intelligence-means-for-homebuyers-real-estate-market.html">real estate agents</a> can even use the technology to predict when properties might be ready to go on the market. Artificial intelligence is becoming essential for the fintech industry, especially when addressing real-time data tracking, and its use may continue to rise over the coming years. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="558" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-03-1024x558.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25832" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-03-1024x558.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-03-300x163.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-03-768x418.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/smaller-03.png 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Fintech trends can be exciting to watch, but they also provide plenty of opportunities for investments, whether you’re looking at purchasing stock in companies using Banking as a Service or you want to use AI to manage your investments and help you begin investing in real estate. Click here to learn more about <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/">DiversyFund</a> and its place in the fintech world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/07/three-fintech-trends-for-investors-to-watch/">Three Fintech Trends for Investors to Watch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/01/07/three-fintech-trends-for-investors-to-watch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public REITs vs Private REITs: Understanding the Differences</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/09/public-reits-vs-private/</link>
					<comments>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/09/public-reits-vs-private/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private reits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public reits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[REITs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=25798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to investing in REITs, there are two main choices available: private REITs and public REITs. Both options have unique benefits, so it’s a good idea to learn...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/09/public-reits-vs-private/">Public REITs vs Private REITs: Understanding the Differences</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When it comes to investing in REITs, there are two main choices available: private REITs and public REITs. Both options have unique benefits, so it’s a good idea to learn more about these different types of investments before making a decision about your portfolio. Take a closer look at traded and non-traded REITs to see which one is right for you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Public REITs</h2>



<p>Public REITs, also referred to as traded REITs or publicly traded, are real estate investment trusts that are traded on the stock exchange. This means the shares are made available to the public for purchase, and the shares can also be sold. REITs traded on major stock exchanges are <a href="https://www.sec.gov/files/reits.pdf">registered with the SEC</a> and may be subject to certain regulations. You can invest in a publicly traded REIT using a self-managed brokerage account or by going through a broker.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One reason some investors like public REITs is the liquidity of the investment. Shares can be sold in much the same way as stocks, so it’s easier to respond to market highs and lows. However, traded REITs are subject to market volatility in ways that other REITs might not be, which can make them less likely candidates for long-term investing and wealth building.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/NonTraded-REITs-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25800" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/NonTraded-REITs-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/NonTraded-REITs-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/NonTraded-REITs-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/NonTraded-REITs-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/NonTraded-REITs.png 1734w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Private REITs</h2>



<p>Non-traded REITs fall into two separate categories: private REITS and public non-listed REITs. Much like their name implies, these types of real estate investment trusts are not listed or traded on any stock markets. This means they aren’t as liquid as their publicly traded counterparts and are more ideal for use as long-term investments. Non-traded REITs also have some significant <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/pf/08/reit-tax.asp">tax benefits</a>, which can make them more attractive to some investors.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, private and public non-listed REITs do have some critical differences. Anyone looking to invest in a private REIT must be an accredited investor, which means they need to meet certain minimum net worth requirements before investing. These REITs are also not required to register with the SEC, which means there may be some additional risk associated with them. Accredited investors with a certain net worth may be able to take on higher levels of risk, which is why the accreditation is required before investing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Public non-listed REITs, on the other hand, do not require individuals to be accredited. This means anyone can invest in the trusts, as long as they can meet any minimum investment threshold required by the REIT. Unlike private REITs, public non-listed real estate investment trusts are required to register with the SEC. If you’re looking for an investment with potentially lower risks, you may feel more comfortable with this choice.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Is-Traded-or-NonTraded-Right-for-You-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25801" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Is-Traded-or-NonTraded-Right-for-You-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Is-Traded-or-NonTraded-Right-for-You-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Is-Traded-or-NonTraded-Right-for-You-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Is-Traded-or-NonTraded-Right-for-You-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Is-Traded-or-NonTraded-Right-for-You.png 1734w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Public or Private Right for You?</h2>



<p>Investing in any type of REIT lets you become a real estate investor without the burden of loans, building maintenance, and other landlord responsibilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Traded REITs can be a good entry point into real estate for new investors, and they can also be ideal if you’re looking to keep your assets liquid and accessible. However, it’s important to remember that any traded investment is subject to the whims of the market each day. You may see significant highs and lows for your shares, and this can make some investors nervous to hold on to a traded REIT long-term.</p>



<p>Private REITs do carry some extra risk, but for accredited investors, they can also provide greater returns. Depending on your risk comfort level, they can be smart additions to a diverse portfolio designed for long-term growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Public non-traded REITs combine the benefits of publicly traded REITs and private REITs, providing some protections with SEC regulations while offering accessibility to a wide range of individual investors. They can help hedge against inflation and market volatility in ways that traded real estate investment trusts can’t.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Your financial advisor can compare the different REIT options to your financial situations, wealth-building goals, and risk level to help you decide which choice is the right one for you. To learn more about DiversyFund private (public, non-traded) REITs, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/?nl=p">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/09/public-reits-vs-private/">Public REITs vs Private REITs: Understanding the Differences</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/09/public-reits-vs-private/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Passive Investing: Four Hands-Off Options</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/02/passive-investing-hands-off-ideas/</link>
					<comments>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/02/passive-investing-hands-off-ideas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 22:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 102]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passive Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=25790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investing to build wealth doesn’t always mean having to do a lot of work on your own, and passive investing provides a way to grow your money over time without...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/02/passive-investing-hands-off-ideas/">Passive Investing: Four Hands-Off Options</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investing to build wealth doesn’t always mean having to do a lot of work on your own, and passive investing provides a way to grow your money over time without having to monitor markets and trends daily. For some, passive investing is a stress-free way to ensure their money is working for them. This type of investment strategy comes in many forms, so let’s take a closer look at what defines a passive investment and some of the most popular choices available to diversify your portfolio.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Passive Investments Defined</h2>



<p>Passive investing is a strategy that <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/p/passiveinvesting.asp">minimizes buying and selling</a> to build wealth for the long term. It means less work on the part of the investor, and it tends to be less complex than some other investment strategies. Benefits can sometimes include lower fees and better tax benefits, though this depends on the investments you choose and how they are set up. This approach can be a more conservative approach to building wealth, so it’s always important to speak to a financial professional and determine your risk comfort level before making a decision on how to grow your personal portfolio.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Real-Estate-Investing-Through-REITs-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25792" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Real-Estate-Investing-Through-REITs-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Real-Estate-Investing-Through-REITs-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Real-Estate-Investing-Through-REITs-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Real-Estate-Investing-Through-REITs-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Real-Estate-Investing-Through-REITs.png 1734w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate Investing Through REITs</h2>



<p>Investing in rental property real estate is a passive investment option on its own, but individuals buying apartment buildings or homes for rent have to put themselves in the role of landlord. This can mean more work than you might have planned for, and REITs, or Real Estate Investment Trusts, provide a smart alternative. REITs invest in a portfolio of properties and handle the everyday maintenance, rent collection, and all other roles a landlord normally handles. You invest in shares of the REIT in exchange for having all these services taken care of every month. Passive income investment is paid out in the form of dividends, which can then be reinvested to continue a long-term growth strategy. You can learn more about the basics of REIT investing <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/how-real-estate-investments-offer-a-hedge-against-inflation/?nl=p">here</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Index Funds for Passive Investing</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/select/what-are-index-funds/">Index funds</a> come in the form of a mutual fund or an ETF (Exchange-Traded Fund), and they are designed to follow a specific market index. The fund invests in all the companies contained within that market index, providing broad market exposure and creating an instantly diverse portfolio. The Standards &amp; Poors 500 Index (S&amp;P 500 for short) and the Nasdaq Composite Index are just two examples of market indexes a fund might track and follow as a guide for investments. One main benefit of investing in an index fund is that you don’t have to hold individual stocks in your portfolio, which can minimize risk and help you build a long-term strategy for growth. Index funds are also managed for you, so there’s little to do aside from keeping an eye on the fund’s performance over time. It is important to remember that an index fund is still subject to market volatility and may have limited opportunities for significant gains.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Certificates-of-Deposit-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25793" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Certificates-of-Deposit-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Certificates-of-Deposit-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Certificates-of-Deposit-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Certificates-of-Deposit-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Certificates-of-Deposit.png 1734w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Certificates of Deposit</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.investor.gov/introduction-investing/investing-basics/investment-products/certificates-deposit-cds">Certificates of deposit</a>, or CDs, are savings accounts that hold your money for a predetermined amount of time as interest builds. Unlike some of the other passive investment options available, CDs are not tied to the stock market and are federally insured. This makes CDs a good choice for diversifying your portfolio with minimal risk. Upon the maturity date of the CD, you’ll have access to your original deposit plus the accrued interest. <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/banking/what-is-a-cd-ladder">CD ladders</a> can be used to create a stream of passive income, as staggered maturity dates can free up money on a monthly, quarterly, or yearly basis. These ladders consist of several CDs with varied maturity dates, where the funds are reinvested to take advantage of changing interest rates or cashed out to supplement your income. While CDs are a popular choice for passive investment, it’s important to remember that the interest rates may be relatively low, and they will not change even if inflation continues to rise.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crowdfunding for Investors</h2>



<p>Crowdfunding for investors is a relatively new fintech strategy, and it comes in many forms.  Online peer-to-peer lending, for example, is one form of crowdfunding that lets you take the place of traditional loan providers to help fund loans and collect the interest on them. Equity crowdfunding lets you pool money with other investors to fund startups, and some REITs are even based on crowdfunding models. Each of these options provide non-accredited investors the ability to participate in unique opportunities while minimizing the size of their investment. You can learn more about accredited and non-accredited investors <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/what-does-it-take-to-be-accredited/?nl=p">here</a>. Crowdfunding platforms for investors typically have dashboards that provide you with information about your investments so you can track your progress, but they do the most of the work for you, making them suitable options for a diverse passive investment portfolio.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Crowdfunding-for-Investors-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-25794" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Crowdfunding-for-Investors-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Crowdfunding-for-Investors-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Crowdfunding-for-Investors-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Crowdfunding-for-Investors-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Crowdfunding-for-Investors.png 1734w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>There’s no one right or wrong way to approach passive investing. You can use any or all of these strategies to build your portfolio, or you can look for other ways to build wealth over time. To learn more about DiversyFund and how its strategies can work with your plan for passive investing, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/about/?nl=p">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/02/passive-investing-hands-off-ideas/">Passive Investing: Four Hands-Off Options</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2022/12/02/passive-investing-hands-off-ideas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
