<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Real Estate Archives - DiversyFund</title>
	<atom:link href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/category/real-estate/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/category/real-estate/</link>
	<description>Real Estate Investing Platform</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 22:56:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Art of Timing: Exiting a Multifamily Investment</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/15/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investing in multifamily real estate can be a lucrative venture, but you’ll want to begin considering your possible exit strategy right away. To be clear, an exit strategy isn’t a...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/15/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment/">The Art of Timing: Exiting a Multifamily Investment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investing in multifamily real estate can be a lucrative venture, but you’ll want to begin considering your possible exit strategy right away. To be clear, an exit strategy isn’t a way to bail on your investment. It is actually a plan to eventually sell a property so you can make the most of current market conditions and help maximize returns on your multifamily investments.. We’ll delve a little deeper into the concept of an exit strategy to help you learn more about the concept, how it works, and what the different options are for exiting your real estate investment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reasons to Exit</h2>



<p>Exiting a multifamily investment is essential for realizing a full return on the investment. The sale of the property brings liquidity to your investment, so you can recover the physical cash for your initial investment as well as any profits realized from the sale. In some cases, investors may decide to exit an investment if it’s not performing as expected. Investors serving as both the sole owner of a property and a full-time landlord for its tenants might consider exiting due to the workload that comes with single ownership of a multifamily asset.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Multifamily Exit Strategies</h2>



<p>There are several different exit strategies available for investors, but we will be covering the main four here. Each of these exit options has different pros and cons, so you’ll want to consider each one carefully as you craft your plan.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26261" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Buy and Hold</h2>



<p>The concept of buy and hold means simply that once you’ve made your investment, you hold on to the asset and give it time to build equity. Some investors plan on keeping a property in their portfolios for 5-10 years. This provides plenty of time to improve the property, increase cash flow, and potentially increase the value of the asset  before the eventual sale. <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/">REITs and single-asset offerings</a> from DiversyFund employ the buy and hold strategy. </p>



<p>One potential downside for buy and hold is the lack of liquidity. While you can see monthly income in the form of rents (if you are a direct owner) or dividends (if you are part of an investor group), your core investment remains inaccessible until the sale of the property is complete. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Refinance to Leverage Current Market Conditions</h2>



<p>Refinancing is an option that lets you keep your multifamily property while taking advantage of current market conditions. A refinance when interest rates are lower can be used to pay off the initial investment, and it can also give you access to extra cash you can use to improve the property. It’s a good idea to keep an eye on interest rates throughout the length of your investment so you can make the decision to refinance when conditions are at their most favorable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Choosing to refinance only works if you’re willing to keep your investment longer. If you feel you’ve already maximized the return on your multifamily asset, selling might be a better option.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The 1031 exchange</h2>



<p>If you’re ready to sell your existing property but have your eye on a new asset to replace it with, the <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/financial-edge/0110/10-things-to-know-about-1031-exchanges.aspx">1031 Exchange</a> can be an advantageous exit strategy option. This concept lets you essentially “swap” on property for another, deferring any capital gains taxes in the process. You can use the 1031 exchange as many times as you like, provided you follow all the rules and regulations of the tax law. Remember that selling a property outright without a replacement investment makes the sale subject to capital gains taxes. The 1031 exchange basically lets you continue to defer until you sell without a replacement investment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are a couple of downsides to this exit strategy. The rules can be difficult to follow if you don’t have a tax professional helping you, and the process means your investment continues to be illiquid. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Open Up to Additional Investors</h2>



<p>If you are a sole investor in a property, opening it up to additional investors can provide you with some additional financial freedom. You don’t have to carry the burden of managing the asset on your own, and you can share risk with the other investors. For an asset you already own, this process gives you access to extra cash for capital or value-add improvements. You can also use this concept before you purchase a property. Pooling money together with other investors makes it easier to invest in larger or more expensive properties without having to put up all of the cash.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sharing an asset with other investors isn’t for everyone. You’ll need to give up some power and control, as each investor has a say in how the property is handled and when it’s ready for sale. You’ll want to make sure you thoroughly vet any potential investor so you have a good idea of who you are sharing your investment with.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26262" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Timing Your Exit</h2>



<p>The timing of any exit strategy is crucial, so it’s important to keep a close watch on current market conditions, interest rates, and inflation throughout the length of your investment. Multifamily investment wealth preservation, or the art of keeping and maintaining the wealth gained through your real estate investment, relies on leveraging current conditions to make the most informed decisions about your property. Some things to consider when timing your exit are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Tax implications</strong>: How will the sale impact your tax situation? There are ways to offset or defer tax liability, such as a 1031 exchange, to help you maximize returns on multifamily investments.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Interest Rates: </strong>Can lower interest rates make refinancing a better option than selling? Refinancing means spending less to own the property you’ve purchased, and it can also help you build equity while deploying a buy and hold strategy.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Market Volatility:</strong> During times of market volatility, owning real estate can provide a hedge against inflation and unpredictable markets. If you believe the value of your property can continue to increase in the future, does it make more sense to hold on to the property as a buffer against a volatile market?</li>



<li><strong>Investment Capital Preservation: </strong>Real estate can be used in an investment capital preservation strategy, making it a unique addition to an investment portfolio. The multifamily asset you invest in can help you preserve capital and avoid loss, so holding on to these types of investments for the long-term may make more sense than selling.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Looking at comps for other properties in the area can help you decide when it’s time to employ a hard exit strategy. If you’re hoping to take advantage of the 1031 exchange and will be financing the new purchase, it’s also a good idea to monitor interest rates. A financial expert can also help you determine the right timing for any of the exit strategies we’ve discussed above, even when to consider adding an outside investor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investing in real estate is about more than just buying properties. It truly is like the old song goes… you do have to know when to hold them. As always, you’ll want to consult with your financial expert before making any money moves, including your exit strategy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/15/the-art-of-timing-exiting-a-multifamily-investment/">The Art of Timing: Exiting a Multifamily Investment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From A to C: Exploring Multifamily Real Estate Investment Classes</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/28/from-a-to-c-exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 17:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing in real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[REITs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investors looking to put their money into multifamily real estate can better inform their decisions by learning about the different multifamily real estate investment classes. Each class carries different risk...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/28/from-a-to-c-exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes/">From A to C: Exploring Multifamily Real Estate Investment Classes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investors looking to put their money into multifamily real estate can better inform their decisions by learning about the different multifamily real estate investment classes. Each class carries different risk factors, potential rewards, and unique characteristics. While there is no one class that’s ideal for every investor, some classes may be more attractive, depending on your financial goals and risk tolerance. Here’s a closer look at each of these multifamily real estate investment classes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Class A</h2>



<p>Class A refers to properties with luxury amenities and/or are in the most attractive locations, which often garner the highest possible rents. They are also known as core investments, known for their lower financial risk and reliable cash flow. For some investors, owning a Class A property is the ultimate goal, but there are some drawbacks for both renters and owners/investors. In times of economic uncertainty, renters in luxury apartments may look to save money by ending their current leases and moving to Class B properties. Investors with Class A holdings may also find very little room for growth, particularly when inflation and economic stressors make it difficult to increase rental rates.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26238" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Class B</h2>



<p>Class B properties are those in need of some capital improvements or that are slightly outside of the more desirable city center. Also known as core plus investments, they carry some risk for investors but can still be considered solid additions to a portfolio if handled properly. Renters of Class B or core plus properties trade off access to luxury amenities and nearby attractions to save a bit of money. Investors like these properties because they can improve them and increase rents without having to undertake massive renovation and renewal projects. Class B properties can be improved while maintaining affordability for tenants, but investors can also put a bit more money into them to upgrade to a Class A designation. Investors look to Class B assets for their affordability, potential for dependable cash flow, and minimal need for renovations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Class C</h2>



<p>Class C refers to properties that are in less desirable areas or those that are in serious need of repair and renovation. You may also hear these properties referred to as value-add investments, or those that carry higher risk and may be in need of significant management changes and capital improvements before turning a profit. Investors can purchase these assets at a considerable savings, but they will most likely need to spend quite a bit of money on repairs and filling vacancies. The location and state of the properties can also limit the potential for growth through increased rents. However, it is possible to find a great Class C property and give it enough TLC to make the jump to a Class B asset.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Economic Trends Impacting Class A Properties</h2>



<p>Current economic conditions can have an impact on the decisions renters and investors make. In times of uncertainty, such as with the current inflation crisis and potential recession on the horizon, renters of all classes may look for ways to save money. For renters of Class A properties, this often means ending their leases and looking for more affordable Class B options.</p>



<p>Today’s multifamily real estate market also faces the issue of a potential surplus in luxury apartments, which many may no longer be able to afford. According to <a href="https://multifamily.fanniemae.com/news-insights/multifamily-market-commentary/2023-multifamily-market-outlook-turbulence-ahead">Fannie Mae</a>, much of the rental surplus in the U.S. is concentrated among luxury units in just 15 metro areas (including New York, Washington, D.C., and Los Angeles. This means that the surplus is only accessible to a limited few, while renters in other secondary and tertiary markets are left looking for available units. Class B investment properties can fill this need, giving investors the potential for profits while making affordable housing more accessible to those looking to move out of Class A properties and pricing.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Class B or core plus properties are in a unique position in the current economy, providing more affordable housing opportunities in more communities when compared to their Class A or core counterparts. Investors can purchase these assets at a lower price, albeit with some increased risk, and help meet the housing demand that exists in the market today. With the right capital investments, these assets can be more attractive to renters than even some luxury apartment offerings.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26239" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>Class B or core plus multifamily real estate assets meet a need in today’s housing market, helping bridge the gap for those who want to save money and make more conservative financial moves in times of uncertainty.  If you are looking to begin investing in multifamily real estate, there are many opportunities to diversify your portfolio with Class B assets. You can learn more about DiversyFund’s offerings and how they can fit into your plan for building wealth <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/28/from-a-to-c-exploring-multifamily-real-estate-investment-classes/">From A to C: Exploring Multifamily Real Estate Investment Classes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investing in Affordable Housing: Meeting the Demand for Workforce Housing</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/05/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily assets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate markets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While housing markets experience ups and downs, the need for workforce housing remains stable, making it a potential option for real estate investment. Affordable housing is needed for essential workers...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/05/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing/">Investing in Affordable Housing: Meeting the Demand for Workforce Housing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>While housing markets experience ups and downs, the need for workforce housing remains stable, making it a potential option for real estate investment. Affordable housing is needed for essential workers and other blue collar workers, which means investors can look to more affordable multifamily properties to purchase and grow their profits. We’ll take a closer look at how real estate investors like you can help meet the demand for housing and expand their portfolios with smart, strategic real estate investments.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding Class B Multifamily Investments</h2>



<p>Multifamily real estate properties can be broken down into three categories: Class A, Class B, and Class C. Class A tends to include high-end or luxury properties, and Class C are older buildings that tend to need extensive repairs and renovations. Class B multifamily investments are ideal for use as workforce housing, as they tend to be slightly older or are situated away from city centers, thereby offering affordability for both investors and renters alike. They may require some repairs and renovations, but not as much as those needed for Class C properties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lower potential rents (when compared to Class A properties) are often the result of fewer amenities, but this means they can be more attractive to middle-class workers.. For investors, these properties may be ideal because they attract tenants with stable incomes and may also have lower vacancy rates (when compared to Class C properties).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26219" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Investing in Emerging Markets</h2>



<p><a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/growth-trends-emerging-real-estate-markets/">Emerging markets</a>, also known as tertiary markets, are those with a population of less than 1 million people and the potential for growth. They can be a smart choice for real estate investors looking to meet the demands of workforce housing. These markets tend to see positive job growth as employers move away from the expense and hassle of operating businesses in city centers. When jobs move to secondary and tertiary markets, the workforce looks to find affordable available housing in these new areas. <br>Residents in these markets can afford to spend less than 30% of their income on housing, and investors can provide housing options to meet their budgets by purchasing and renovating Class B properties. <a href="https://www.reit.com/news/reit-magazine/march-april-2021/reits-are-helping-bridge-gap">Many REITs</a> are using this strategy to give investors a convenient way to expand their real estate portfolios while helping fill the need for housing in emerging markets with expanding populations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Investing In Sun Belt Markets</h2>



<p>Not all growing markets are technically considered emerging markets. Some markets in slightly bigger cities are seeing explosions in both population and job growth, and that includes many cities throughout the Sun Belt. Areas including Houston, Dallas-Fort Worth, Charlotte, Tampa, and Phoenix, are showing promise as potentially lucrative locations for multifamily real estate investment. New jobs and new residents in these southern cities mean an increased need for workforce housing, and new construction projects might not be enough to meet the demand. Investors ready to seek out Class B properties for purchase and renovation may find it easy to keep vacancy rates low and bring in consistent income in these Sun Belt Markets.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26220" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Smart Value-Add Strategies</h2>



<p>Class B multifamily properties may not have the same level of amenities as their Class A counterparts, but investors can seek out smart value-add strategies to help attract new tenants and provide a better quality of living for those seeking out affordable housing. Strategic renovations can improve the overall value of each property, resulting in potentially better cash flow and higher rents. Some examples of smart value-add strategies that give existing and new tenants access to desirable amenities include:</p>



<ul>
<li>New appliances and light fixtures</li>



<li>Smart door locks and thermostats</li>



<li>Outdoor security systems</li>



<li>Updated HVAC and plumbing systems</li>
</ul>



<p>While these amenities don’t match the perks of dog runs, movie theater rooms, and fitness centers found in luxury apartment buildings and complexes, they do make it easier to attract tenants and increase the overall value of your investment. The benefit of investing in a Class B property is that the need for major renovations isn’t as great, freeing up your capital for use on improvements that help make your multifamily asset stand out in a growing market.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>There will always be a need for affordable workforce housing. The concept of profitable real estate investing doesn’t have to be at odds with providing workers safe, comfortable, and affordable housing. To learn more about how DiversyFund leverages Class B properties to benefit those looking for housing and those looking to invest in real estate, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/08/05/investing-in-affordable-housing-meeting-the-demand-for-workforce-housing/">Investing in Affordable Housing: Meeting the Demand for Workforce Housing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Multifamily Investing Showdown: Suburban vs. Urban Markets</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/14/multifamily-investing-showdown-suburban-vs-urban-markets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 22:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Location is always essential when choosing to invest in multifamily real estate, and that means knowing whether to choose properties in suburban or urban areas. Both options have pros and...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/14/multifamily-investing-showdown-suburban-vs-urban-markets/">Multifamily Investing Showdown: Suburban vs. Urban Markets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Location is always essential when choosing to invest in multifamily real estate, and that means knowing whether to choose properties in suburban or urban areas. Both options have pros and cons, and knowing how to compare the two can help you make the right moves for your portfolio. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Urban Multifamily Investments</h2>



<p>Multifamily real estate properties in urban areas have the benefit of being located close to available jobs, schools, and amenities. These markets tend to be densely populated and may have lots of options for real estate investment. Urban markets can often be considered primary markets, or those with a population of 5 million or more. The vast size of the cities, along with the job opportunities and other amenities, can make them more desirable for residents.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Pro: Rental Demand</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>The demand for housing in urban markets tends to be greater due to the increased population in big cities. People moving to the city for school, job opportunities, or simply a different way of life are in need of housing, and the dense makeup of these areas means they may be more likely to move to an apartment instead of buying a home. The diverse pool of potential tenants provides unique opportunities for multifamily real estate investors, who can be more discerning when selecting residents for their properties.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Pro: Rent Potential</strong></p>



<p>The cost of living tends to be higher in urban communities, and that includes rents. Investors looking to charge the market rate for units in their buildings can command more per month than they might in a suburban location, which means the potential for greater cash flow in the long run. Investing in a building or complex that’s close to public transportation and within walking distance to schools and shopping centers can command even more in monthly rents, so it’s important to identify key locations within an urban area to maximize profits and cash flow for your investment.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Con: Higher Purchase Prices</strong></p>



<p>One of the reasons apartments in urban areas command higher rents is the higher purchase price for properties. Investors may find multifamily properties to be more expensive than in the suburbs, and the cost increases closer to city centers. Competition between multiple potential investors in the city can also drive up the cost of real estate. This means you may spend a considerable amount more for an asset near shopping districts, train stations, and other amenities renters find desirable when looking for a new residence. HIgher purchase prices can also impact the potential for profitability with lower profit margins.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Con: City Codes and Zoning Ordinances</strong></p>



<p>Cities tend to have more housing codes and zoning ordinances for landlords to abide by. For example, codes in the City of <a href="https://www.chicago.gov/city/en/depts/doh/provdrs/renters/svcs/know-your-rights--fair-notice-ordinance.html">Chicago</a> state landlords must give tenants living in an apartment for 3 years or more 120 days notice in the event of a rent increase, and tenants living in an apartment for under 3 years must be notified 60 days in advance. This creates an extra obstacle for landlords and property managers trying to maintain a property’s profitability. Zoning ordinances can cause problems when investors are ready to renovate, expand, or even tear down an existing structure to build a new development. Suburban and rural markets may not have the same challenges. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26200" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Suburban Multifamily Investments</h2>



<p>Suburban communities are also referred to as emerging or secondary markets, depending on their population. They sit outside of the city but provide easy commuter access to urban areas. Lower costs of living and increasing housing options make suburbs attractive to those looking to escape from the dense population and expensive living conditions of the city.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Pro: Family-Friendly Environment</strong></p>



<p>Renters looking to take advantage of better schools, more parks, and more of a family-friendly atmosphere can find the suburbs to be more desirable compared to the city. Quiet streets and more of a community atmosphere also tend to attract new renters, particularly those who want to get out of the city but are unable to afford the cost of homeownership. This means increased opportunities for multifamily real estate investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Pro: Rent Potential</strong></p>



<p>While we listed rent potential as a pro for urban markets, it’s increasingly becoming a benefit for suburban markets as well. With so many people flocking to the suburbs, the divide between urban and suburban costs of living is starting to narrow. A recent report showed approximately <a href="https://www.rent.com/research/suburban-growth-outpacing-core-city/">90% of suburban communities</a> around Dallas-Fort Worth outpaced rent growth in the city center. Similar results were also reported in Houston, Chicago, and Nashville, just to name a few. The potential for increased cash flow in the suburbs is growing.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Con: Limited Services and Amenities</strong></p>



<p>There may be plenty of reasons renters look to the suburbs for housing, but there are also some downsides. Limited public transportation options and longer commutes can be deterrents for those looking to move outside of the city center. Fewer options for restaurants, museums, and nightlife are also potential drawbacks. Suburban sprawl also limits the walkability in many areas, and those currently living in cities with plenty of shops and restaurants within walking distance might consider this a dealbreaker. Additionally, some suburbs have fewer options for hospitals and healthcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Con: Limited Supply</strong></p>



<p>Suburban communities are expanding, but supply chain issues and labor shortages leftover from the pandemic are still impacting the housing industry. Investors in some areas are finding limited options for purchasing existing properties, and development projects are taking much longer to complete in some cases. Limited supply can drive up the cost of real estate, making suburban multifamily real estate more expensive than expected.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26201" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/multifamily-real-estate-investing-comparing-suburban-vs-urban-markets_03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>Making strategic decisions about where to invest in real estate means doing plenty of market research. There are benefits to investing in both urban and suburban areas, so choosing the right option all comes down to the details about each individual property. Housing trends can shift over time, with people moving into and out of city centers in waves. You’ll want to keep an eye on trends and current market conditions when adding real estate to your portfolio. To learn more about DiversyFund’s offerings in urban and suburban markets, or to simply learn more about how we can help you begin investing in multifamily real estate, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/why-real-estate/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/14/multifamily-investing-showdown-suburban-vs-urban-markets/">Multifamily Investing Showdown: Suburban vs. Urban Markets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Market Report &#8211; San Antonio Multifamily &#8211; Q1 2023</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/16/market-report-san-antonio-multifamily-q1-2023/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 22:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2023 Q1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market Overview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Antonio Multifamily]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The San Antonio multifamily real estate market offers some unique opportunities for investment, and although the market has slowed a bit in recent years, the area is worth a closer...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/16/market-report-san-antonio-multifamily-q1-2023/">Market Report &#8211; San Antonio Multifamily &#8211; Q1 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The San Antonio multifamily real estate market offers some unique opportunities for investment, and although the market has slowed a bit in recent years, the area is worth a closer look. We’ll review some statistics and key points investors like you need to know to make an informed decision about choosing a real estate investment in San Antonio.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vacancy Rates</h2>



<p>There are signs of a recent softening in the San Antonio real estate market, with vacancy rates in Q1 estimated at 8.7 percent, but the 12-month outlook indicates this number will decline. A strong job market with 43,000 new employment opportunities in the area shows San Antonio is still a city poised for growth. Some sub-markets fared better than others, with Kerrville and portions of the northwestern side of the city coming in under 6 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s important to note that home sales also saw a decrease, presumably in part due to increases in interest rates. Home sales in San Antonio declined by 28.9% in December 2022, which may point to ongoing needs for rental housing in the area.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investors will want to take a close look at the vacancy rates for the area of any investment, but it’s important to take local job opportunities and infrastructure improvements into account, as they can impact the rates going forward. Overall, the vacancy outlook for San Antonio and the surrounding area remains stable.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26152" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rent Rates</h2>



<p>Rents in San Antonio continued to show growth potential through Q1 of 2023. The region recorded an average cost per square foot of $1.49, with effective rents averaging around $1,300 per month. For comparison, the fair market rate for a two-bedroom apartment is <a href="https://www.rentdata.org/states/texas/2023">$907</a> in the State of Texas. Low supply for available rental units combined with ongoing demand may account for some of the growth in San Antonio and the surrounding areas. <br>The San Antonio area also showed an increase in income for 2022, with average hourly earnings increasing <a href="https://www.dallasfed.org/research/indicators/sa/2023/sa2302#:~:text=Overall%20in%202022%2C%20payroll%20employment,services%2C%20which%20declined%200.5%20percent.">5.5%</a>. This rate outpaced the increase statewide, indicating San Antonians are better able to afford increased rents when compared to the previous year. The city also tends to have a lower cost of living than other major metro areas, making it potentially more desirable during periods of high inflation and national economic uncertainty.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New Construction</h2>



<p>As of Q1 2023, an estimated 23,000 new units were under construction. This added supply is needed to meet the demand for renters in the San Antonio area, as supply has been historically low for the last few years. The new construction projects in the city span all price ranges, from small, affordable units to posh luxury units. A <a href="https://www.mysanantonio.com/realestate/article/san-antonio-apartment-projects-17633249.php">$54 million development</a> in the popular River Walk area is expected to deliver 263 luxury apartments, adding to the ongoing growth and development for the neighborhood. Mixed-use highrises are even helping to create more of a neighborhood feel throughout the city, combining retail and service elements with desirable residential units.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Supply chain issues and availability of some construction materials continue to be ongoing challenges for new construction projects, and recent rises in costs due to inflation may compound the problems. However, it does look like there are many new developments in San Antonio for investors to be excited about. The addition of new units may also provide additional opportunities for growth with existing multifamily assets throughout the city and surrounding areas. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate Sales</h2>



<p>Multifamily real estate sales in San Antonio have shown signs of growth since the end of 2022. In Q1 alone, there were 20 total sales that included 4,326 units. This growth may be a bit surprising given increases in interest rates over the past year, but the sales underscore the potential for San Antonio as a continuously growing metro area. This sales combined with the new construction projects provide plenty of reasons to be optimistic about the San Antonio real estate market.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26153" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/market-report-san-antonio-q1-2023-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">San Antonio Economic Outlook</h2>



<p>For Q1 and beyond, the overall economic outlook for San Antonio remains strong. Job market growth and low unemployment numbers make the city desirable for those wanting to relocate to a more affordable city without compromising on job opportunities. In fact, the average cost of living in San Antonio is 8% lower than the national average. Consumer spending continues to remain strong, and not just when it comes to necessities. In January 2023, restaurant reservations increased by <a href="https://www.dallasfed.org/research/indicators/sa/2023/sa2302#:~:text=Overall%20in%202022%2C%20payroll%20employment,services%2C%20which%20declined%200.5%20percent.">12.1%</a>. Inflation and interest rates continue to be a concern in San Antonio as with the rest of the country.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>The outlook for multifamily real estate in San Antonio remains positive, with stable vacancy rates and some continued growth in rent rates. A strong job economy makes the city a desirable place to move to and gives current residents reason to stay. With new construction projects underway, there will be more supply to meet the demand for rental housing, providing alternatives for those who are unable to afford the ever-increasing cost of home ownership. Investors may choose to purchase multifamily assets on their own, but there are also many opportunities to invest in real estate without taking on all the risk alone. <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/the-independent/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic%20&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-6-16">Single-asset offerings</a> for accredited investors and REITs for both non-accredited and accredited investors let you invest in the market alongside other like-minded investors. </p>



<p><em>Information in this report provided by ApartmentTrends.com by Austin Investor Interests, LLC</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/16/market-report-san-antonio-multifamily-q1-2023/">Market Report &#8211; San Antonio Multifamily &#8211; Q1 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demographic Shifts and Multifamily Real Estate: A Look into the Future</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/09/demographic-shifts-and-multifamily-real-estate-a-look-into-the-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 22:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily real estate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recent increases and inflation and the leftover effects of COVID have left many wondering what the real estate market has in store, but there are many reasons to remain optimistic...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/09/demographic-shifts-and-multifamily-real-estate-a-look-into-the-future/">Demographic Shifts and Multifamily Real Estate: A Look into the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Recent increases and inflation and the leftover effects of COVID have left many wondering what the real estate market has in store, but there are many reasons to remain optimistic about the future of multifamily real estate investing. From shifts in attitudes toward home ownership to the rapid urbanization of smaller communities, multifamily real estate properties are more relevant than ever. Let’s take a closer look at just what the future has in store for investors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Urbanization and Emerging Markets</h2>



<p>Rapid urbanization in smaller cities has created a host of emerging markets throughout the country, notably in cities throughout <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/growth-trends-emerging-real-estate-markets/">Texas</a>, Florida, North Carolina, and other states throughout the South. While increases in population lead to an increased demand for housing, the urbanization of these areas has led to interesting housing preferences. There is a growing demand for <a href="https://www.csbj.com/archives/urbanization-national-trends-could-impact-local-market/article_49212956-4696-521d-8639-549ebb6a2172.html">denser housing options</a>, with communities planned around walkability and easy access to neighborhood amenities. This means a need for multifamily real estate properties in emerging rental markets, not just a demand for single-family homes, in an increasing number of cities across the country. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26144" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Preferences of Millennials and Gen Z</h2>



<p>While there is some debate over whether Millennials and Gen Z have been priced out of the option of home ownership or they simply prefer not to own property, the choices these two younger generations are making have serious impacts on the real estate market. An estimated <a href="https://www.rockethomes.com/blog/housing-market/gen-z-home-buying">21% of Gen Zers</a> surveyed were not able to come up with the down payment to purchase a home, and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-04-19/half-of-millennials-own-homes-the-rest-fear-they-ll-never-buy-one#xj4y7vzkg">25% of Millennial renters</a> reported they’ve given up on the possibility of owning a home.<br><br>With two generations of Americans preferring or needing to rent in 2023 and beyond, the demand for affordable rental properties remains dependable, creating a positive outlook for the multifamily real estate market. However, developers must meet their needs and preferences. <a href="https://www.rentcafe.com/blog/rental-market/market-snapshots/generation-z-most-techy-research-focused-instagram-loving-generation-renters/">Younger generations</a> want homes that integrate technology with traditional amenities, such as smart locks and thermostats. High-speed internet and access to gym/fitness centers also rank high on the list of must-haves for young renters. Real estate investors will want to look at these trends when making decisions on where to invest and how to improve properties.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sustainable Development </h2>



<p>Sustainability is important to younger generations of renters too, and developers are integrating eco-friendly principles into new construction projects. Sustainable development can help boost local real estate markets and appeal to Millennials and Gen Z, as well as other generations of renters. Energy-efficient lighting and appliances are easy to incorporate into both new and existing developments, and new multifamily projects can incorporate ethically sourced green building materials, such as reclaimed lumber, to help reduce waste and construction costs. <br>There are many benefits for investors to seek out sustainable options for new developments and capital improvements on existing buildings, including <a href="https://www.usgbc.org/articles/ira-update-it-s-go-green-building-tax-incentives">tax incentives</a> for installing EV charging stations and rooftop solar systems. Adding these green amenities can attract new tenants at higher rents to improve cash flow potential.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26145" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/the-future-of-multifamily-real-estate-2023-and-beyond-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hedging Against Inflation and Market Volatility</h2>



<p>Investing in multifamily real estate offers a unique <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/how-real-estate-investments-offer-a-hedge-against-inflation/">hedge against inflation</a> and market volatility, particularly in today’s complex financial market. While the single-family housing market has been hit by high inflation and even higher interest rates, the impact on multifamily housing is markedly different. People may not be able to afford single-family homes in 2023, and current homeowners may be hesitant to sell when interest rates are high, which means renters may need to continue renting for longer. The demand for rental housing has not dropped significantly, providing a unique opportunity for investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Similarly, real estate can also provide a hedge against market volatility going forward. While stock markets respond quickly to global politics, breaking financial news, and other world events, the real estate market can’t respond as quickly. This means real estate doesn’t see the volatile highs and lows that stocks often experience. Investors looking to diversify their portfolios in 2023 may want to consider real estate as a way to protect against potentially unstable stock markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>New markets popping up across the country combined with younger generations of renters wanting affordable, sustainable housing options they can depend on provides a promising outlook for multifamily real estate in 2023 and the coming years. <a href="https://diversyfund.com/why-real-estate/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-6-9">Investing in real estate</a> can help you create a diverse portfolio and hedge against inflation and market volatility.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/09/demographic-shifts-and-multifamily-real-estate-a-look-into-the-future/">Demographic Shifts and Multifamily Real Estate: A Look into the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doing the Math: Analyzing Cash Flow in Multifamily Investing</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/14/doing-the-math-analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-investing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 21:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cash flow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cash flow is a key to a successful investment in multifamily real estate assets, and it’s a good idea for investors to become familiar with all the factors that go...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/14/doing-the-math-analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-investing/">Doing the Math: Analyzing Cash Flow in Multifamily Investing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cash flow is a key to a successful investment in multifamily real estate assets, and it’s a good idea for investors to become familiar with all the factors that go into analyzing cash flow. We’ll take a closer look at just what cash flow is and how it can be analyzed to determine the profitability of a property.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Real Estate Cash Flow</h2>



<p>Simply put, cash flow is the money coming in and going out each month for any given real estate property. Cash flow analysis is used to review these funds to help determine profitability. Incoming funds include rent, late fees, income from vending and laundry machines, and administration fees, just to name a few. Costs associated with running the property are also taken into account when analyzing cash flow. Property taxes, insurance, and maintenance fees make up just some of the many costs that go into operating a multifamily real estate asset.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26065" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Net Operating Income</h2>



<p>When the books are balanced each month, investors or property owners can determine their <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/n/noi.asp">net operating income</a> (NOI) to measure profitability. While there are several factors that play into the NOI, it is essentially the gross revenue generated each month minus regular monthly expenses. These expenses don’t include any one-time costs, such as major renovations or any costs that might be written off in the future. Vacancy rates also play into a property’s NOI. If 100% of the units are not leased, the vacancies are counted as lost income. Once expenses are subtracted from the gross income, you’re left with your NOI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Debt Service</h2>



<p>One regular expense not listed in the calculations for a property’s NOI is debt service, which is the amount of money required to pay any loans and interest from financing the purchase of the property. Any review of cash flow for a property should take debt service into account, typically through the analysis of the property’s <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/dscr.asp">debt-service coverage ratio</a> (DSCR). The formula for this calculation is the property’s NOI divided by the total debt service. This final number will give you a clear indication of the asset’s profitability. A DSCR that is too low might indicate that a property is over-leveraged and financially risky, while one that is higher indicates the property can cover its debts and then some. Investors can use this information to determine where to cut costs or if increases in rents are needed to generate profitable cash flow each month.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Strategies for Optimizing Cash Flow</h2>



<p>There are a number of different ways to optimize cash flow in a multifamily real estate asset. The property management company in charge of handling an asset can evaluate current rental rates to ensure they are at or above current market rates, and additional steps can be taken to reduce the number of vacancies. Renovations can attract new renters willing to pay more for the available units, which can increase monthly cash flow going forward. Of course, there are other more creative ways to bring in more money each month, such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>Convert vacant units into short-term vacation rentals</li>



<li>Add vending machines to common areas</li>



<li>Charge for premium parking (paid assigned spots closer to the building)</li>



<li>Convert unused space into paid storage units/lockers for tenants</li>



<li>Offer paid friends and family passes to amenities, such as pools and gym facilities</li>
</ul>



<p>Adding new revenue streams can help boost monthly cash flow, and it can also absorb losses when vacancies do come up.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26066" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-real-estate-investments-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What It Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>Understanding how real estate works – including analyzing cash flow – is essential for investors, and that means knowing how your investments make money. Cash flow is one way multifamily properties make money for their investors. It can represent a long-term stream of steady income for an individual property owner, and it can also represent regular profits for an investment group. Real estate investment strategies centered on long-term growth rely on cash flow until a property is ready to be sold at a profit on the market. To learn more about how DiversyFund uses cash flow analysis to benefit its investors, or to begin your wealth building journey with real estate, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-4-14-23">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/14/doing-the-math-analyzing-cash-flow-in-multifamily-investing/">Doing the Math: Analyzing Cash Flow in Multifamily Investing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Passive Pointers: The Importance of Property Management</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/31/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 19:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passive Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investing in real estate doesn’t mean you have to become a full-time landlord; property management companies are essential to multifamily real estate investing. Whether you’re considering purchasing a small apartment...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/31/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management/">Passive Pointers: The Importance of Property Management</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investing in real estate doesn’t mean you have to become a full-time landlord; property management companies are essential to multifamily real estate investing. Whether you’re considering purchasing a small apartment building on your own or investing in a real estate fund, property management plays an essential role in your investment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What a Property Management Company Does</h2>



<p>A property management company handles all of the day-to-day tasks of running a multifamily asset. They are the face of the property, interacting with tenants and making sure everything runs smoothly. Some companies offer more services than others, but the essential duties of maintenance and repair, rent collection, and tenant screening are typically involved. This makes owning property a hands-off investment that still has the potential for steady monthly income, but how does property management add value to an investment? Let’s take a closer look at the benefits of hiring a management company.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26053" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tenant Acquisition and Retention</h2>



<p>Low vacancy rates and high retention rates are essential for running a profitable multifamily asset. Property management companies can help drive these numbers in several ways:</p>



<ul>
<li>Tenant screening: Handling background checks, income/employment verification, and application processing to help ensure vacancies are filled with high-quality tenants.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Marketing: Advertising new vacancies to attract potential tenants who can afford to pay rents at market rate or above while also positioning the property as a desirable place to live.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Tenant management: Being available and responsive to tenant requests, making sure issues, such as repairs, are attended to in a timely fashion.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>The tenants are at the center of what makes a property profitable, and managing both the quality of the residents and their satisfaction with the facilities can help drive revenue and retention.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Repairs and Renovations</h2>



<p>Repairs and renovations are essential for both upgrading and maintaining a property, and the management company can handle all the details for both. The best property managers will use reputable contractors and seek out competitive bids to keep costs low while ensuring the resulting work is high-quality. Having trusted emergency plumbers and HVAC contractors on call, for example, can help minimize the cost of needed repairs while giving tenants the services they need in their units. Arranging the work for capital improvements can take away the stress of improving your property while adding value to it. To learn more about capital improvements, check out our previous <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/capital-improvements-how-they-benefit-investors/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-3-31">blog post</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26054" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rent Collection and Finance Management</h2>



<p>Property management companies also handle all the financial aspects of running a property, from collecting rents to generating monthly and quarterly reports. Collecting rent can be a time consuming process, and it can also be stressful for landlords. Keeping track of which tenants paid on time, which ones were late, and how many missed their payments completely can be overwhelming, but property managers have systems in place to track all this information. They also manage the payments of late fees, refunding security deposits, and taking care of any other miscellaneous collection activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reports generated by the property managers make it easy for investors to see how much money comes in every month and monitor expenses. These reports may also show current vacancies, potential rent increases, and other metrics associated with your property. The management company may review reports over time to identify trends and opportunities to increase profitability, making it easy for investors to enjoy passive income instead of acting as landlords. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-04-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26055" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-04-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-04-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-04-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-04-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management-in-multifamily-investing-04.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>The best property management companies will share the goal of a property’s investors: to create a desirable place for tenants to live while also maximizing profitability. Their hard work means investors don’t have to get bogged down in the day-to-day operations of running an apartment building or complex. Whether you’re an individual investor or you’re part of a bigger investment group, having the <a href="https://www.respropmanagement.com/">right property management company</a> involved can help make building long-term growth easier. To learn more about how to invest in multifamily real estate assets with DiversyFund, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-3-31">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/31/passive-pointers-the-importance-of-property-management/">Passive Pointers: The Importance of Property Management</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Market Overview: Monterey and the Greater Salinas Area</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/17/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Greater Salinas metroplex along the Pacific Coast of California holds unique opportunities for investors in multifamily real estate, with promising trends in vacancy rates and rent rates. Salinas consists...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/17/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area/">Market Overview: Monterey and the Greater Salinas Area</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Greater Salinas metroplex along the Pacific Coast of California holds unique opportunities for investors in multifamily real estate, with promising trends in vacancy rates and rent rates. Salinas consists of two areas; Inland Salinas and Monterey. Monterey is the more affluent of the two, while Inland Salinas offers more affordable housing options. For the purposes of this overview, we will focus on the greater metroplex and its most notable submarket, Monterey.&nbsp; A closer look at the overall real estate market offers greater insight into positive trends and how they relate to potential investment outcomes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vacancy Rates</h2>



<p>Vacancy rates in the Salinas metropolitan area remain low at approximately 2.8%, and the limited supply of units may ensure the ongoing demand for rentals in the area. Vacancies for higher-end units remain even lower, showing opportunities for growth to meet the need for 4-star and 5-star properties. The Monterey submarket is holding pace with the Greater Salinas area with a matching 2.8% vacancy rate, though the supply for desirable units remains even lower. Lower vacancy rates for multifamily rental properties in the market and submarket offer promise for potential investors.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26038" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rent Rates</h2>



<p>Increases in rents for Salinas continue to increase at rates deemed reasonable by tenants while still keeping pace with the market. This is good news for investors who want a higher rate of return without driving tenants away. While the overall increase in rents for Salinas is steady at approximately 1.8%, the lower supply and greater demand in Monterey have commanded increases at around 4.3%. Effective rents for 3-star properties in both Salinas and its submarket of Monterey sit at about $2,100. While there are no reports for 4-star/5-star properties in Monterey for the most recent fiscal quarter, similar units in Greater Salinas come in at a respectable $2,500. Even more notable is the increase in Monterey rents over time, with a 61.4% increase over the last 10 years.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New Construction</h2>



<p>The building of new multifamily assets has been severely limited in Salinas, though this may be viewed as a positive with regard to the demand for units in relation to the current supply. No new units were added to the market over the last 12 months, and the trend for the last three years shows limited numbers of just three new units each year. There are opportunities for growth should construction projects get underway, particularly in Monterey where there is a lack of higher-end properties for new tenants to consider. A closer look at Monterey mirrors the trend of the overall area, with just 17 new units being delivered since 2003. With these numbers, it’s reasonable to assume that the stagnation in new construction is not necessarily as closely related to the pandemic and its associated material shortages/supply chain issues when compared to other metroplexes.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="756" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-04-1024x756.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26039" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-04-1024x756.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-04-300x222.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-04-768x567.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-04-1536x1135.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-04.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate Sales</h2>



<p>Sales in the Salinas area have been impacted by rising interest rates, with a noticeable slowdown occurring in 2022. Still, there have been several key sales to note, including the $13.3 million acquisition of an 84-unit property. The average cost per unit has increased to $279,349 from a previous 3-year average of $230,234. Appreciating prices despite increases in interest rates may be indicators of the overall market outlook for the area. The overwhelming majority of recent sales have taken place in Monterey, indicating strength in the market and underscoring the desirability of the area. Prices per unit in Monterey are higher than those in the Greater Salinas area, with a recent average of $300,000 compared to the previous 3-year average of $270,000.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-02-1-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26040" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-02-1-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-02-1-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-02-1-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-02-1-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-02-1.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Greater Salinas Economic Outlook</h2>



<p>Situated just south of San Jose along the Pacific coastline, Metropolitan Salinas is uniquely situated for renters looking for <a href="https://realestate.usnews.com/places/california/salinas">ideal weather and beautiful scenery</a>. A diverse community adds to the desirability of the location. Monterey is home to a famed aquarium, gift shops, and other notable local businesses, further fueling the economy and the overall atmosphere in the area. Salinas, as well as its submarket of Monterey, were hit hard by the pandemic in terms of job losses due to the reliance on tourism and related retail and hospitality jobs. The housing bubble of the Great Recession also impacted the area, and those effects are still being felt. However, the return to business in a post-pandemic world provides hope for jobs and growth to return to the area.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-05-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26041" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-05-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-05-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-05-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-05-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area-05.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>While the area has been hit by both the pandemic and the Great Recession, there is potential for bouncing back in the Greater Salinas area. The unique geographical location and the diverse community both add to the richness of the region, and current rates in vacancies and rents highlight the possibilities for investors. A “return to normal” for tourism and retail may also be key to the future success of Salinas and its Monterey submarket. This is all good news for investors looking to build long-term growth with REITs or <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic-growth&amp;campaign_name=blog-3-17-2023">single-asset multifamily real estate properties</a>.</p>



<p><em>*The information in this article is sourced from a CoStar market report dated 1/18/2023</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/17/market-overview-monterey-and-the-greater-salinas-area/">Market Overview: Monterey and the Greater Salinas Area</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making Moves: Emerging Markets and the Impact of Transportation &#038; Infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/10/emerging-markets-and-infrastructure-impact/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 21:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emerging markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26027</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Emerging markets provide promise for real estate investors, giving them the opportunity to buy low and sell high as demand for properties in those areas increases. There are several factors...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/10/emerging-markets-and-infrastructure-impact/">Making Moves: Emerging Markets and the Impact of Transportation &#038; Infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Emerging markets provide promise for real estate investors, giving them the opportunity to buy low and sell high as demand for properties in those areas increases. There are several factors that make an emerging market, whether it’s a secondary or tertiary market, desirable for both investors and new residents. Infrastructure and transportation improvements can have a significant impact on these markets, so let’s take a closer look at just how much they can transform the landscape of a region.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Public Transportation</h2>



<p>Improvements in public transportation services can connect tertiary markets with larger cities, making them more desirable for commuters looking to move to more affordable areas. Public transit improvements might include expanding bus and rail service to cover a larger area, increasing the frequency of buses, or even adding shuttle services from suburban areas to downtown city centers for the area’s biggest employers. <br>The emerging market of Greenville, South Carolina undertook a large-scale expansion to its <a href="https://www.greenvillesc.gov/316/Swamp-Rabbit-Trail">Swamp Rabbit Trail</a>, a 22-mile walking and biking path. While not a traditional public transit system, it makes the area more accessible for those looking to bike to work or those who want to live in an area with expansive green spaces for outdoor exercise. Plans for the city’s<a href="http://wspa.com/news/local-news/greenlink-to-get-5-8-million-for-bus-stop-improvements/"> Greenlink bus system</a> included federal grant funding to improve bus stops and provide additional services for riders. These public transit improvements, combined with other infrastructure projects, may have driven the area’s real estate growth. The year-over-year increase in multifamily rents for the Greenville area in 2022 was <a href="https://www.colliers.com/en/research/greenville/2021-q4-multifamily-greenville-spartanburg-report">approximately 9.6%</a>, showing just how much public transportation and other upgrades can help emerging markets come into their own.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26029" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Roadway Improvements</h2>



<p>Roadway improvements in secondary and tertiary markets can take many shapes. Some smaller cities need access to major interstate highways to make them more desirable, while others simply require traffic lights in neighborhoods with more congestion due to increases in residents. Improving roadways can make it easier for commuters to move into a neighborhood while still having easy access to the office, and they can also work to prevent traffic problems that result from an influx of new residents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One example of roadway improvements having an impact on an emerging market is Fayetteville, Arkansas. The <a href="https://www.4029tv.com/article/ardot-celebrates-8th-street-interchange-but-some-neighbors-are-concerned/27261189">8th Street Interchange</a> project undertaken in the Fayetteville Suburb of Bentonville provided traffic relief for the town while providing residents easier access to the larger city center via I-49. Connecting the I-49 corridor provides more opportunities for commuters to live outside of downtown Fayetteville, expanding the market and offering real estate investors more options in the area. In 2022, <a href="https://www.kark.com/news/state-news/rent-in-arkansas-up-9-for-2022-study-shows/">Arkansas was among the top 5 states</a> for rent increases, and just one of the recent multifamily property sales in Bentonville topped out at $51 million for a 356-unit development.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other types of roadway upgrades might include adding exits to nearby highways for easy access, adding overpass bridges to alleviate congestion, or widening roads to accommodate more traffic. As these improvements are undertaken, drivability for commuters and local residents improve, creating a more robust and inviting market for real estate growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Neighborhood Revitalization in Emerging Markets</h2>



<p>Revitalizing neighborhoods in emerging markets can breathe new life into a real estate market. New developments and rehabs of historic buildings can bring new businesses to an area as well as new residents. Some cities and towns may look to redevelop once-vibrant city centers, while others may choose to rehab historic neighborhoods to attract both tourists and residents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Richmond, Virginia is one example of a city revitalizing historic neighborhoods and rethinking industrial areas to entice residents and businesses. A former Reynolds metal manufacturing plant was reimagined as a <a href="https://www.thecurrentrichmond.com/neighborhood">mixed-use development</a> with flexible office spaces, apartments, and businesses. The location in a historic neighborhood with access to both the James River, dining, and shopping provided new residents with an incentive to move to the area. The city’s <a href="https://www.rva.gov/parks-recreation/17th-street-market?fbclid=IwAR0vbntrriKzwMnAjxYYTldEJoBwKCPNbxoHR-MPgRARUIV_RjBzVHgRVmI">17th Street Market</a> was rehabbed, giving the state’s longest continuously running farmers market new life and supporting additional local businesses, such as food trucks and other vendors. For 2023, rents are up almost <a href="https://www.apartmentlist.com/rent-report/va/richmond">3%</a> year-over-year, highlighting just how much unique infrastructure improvements can benefit emerging markets. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26030" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/the-impact-of-infrastructure-and-transportation-improvements-on-emerging-real-estate-markets-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Upgrading public transit, improving roadways, and revitalizing neighborhoods can help make secondary and tertiary markets thrive, leading to potential increases in real estate value. As investors look for areas to purchase property, it’s important to look at both past renovations and plans for new infrastructure projects to help determine the strength of the market. To learn more about how DiversyFund can help you invest in real estate in emerging markets, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic-growth&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-3-10-23">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/03/10/emerging-markets-and-infrastructure-impact/">Making Moves: Emerging Markets and the Impact of Transportation &#038; Infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
