<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Investing 101 Archives - DiversyFund</title>
	<atom:link href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/category/investing-101/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/category/investing-101/</link>
	<description>Real Estate Investing Platform</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 21:45:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Crisis-Proofing Your Portfolio: Lessons from Recent Global Events</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/10/06/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Global financial markets are subject to volatility during times of turmoil, and that has been uniquely true for the last few years. A global pandemic, political strife, and ongoing international...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/10/06/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events/">Crisis-Proofing Your Portfolio: Lessons from Recent Global Events</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Global financial markets are subject to volatility during times of turmoil, and that has been uniquely true for the last few years. A global pandemic, political strife, and ongoing international conflicts have had a significant impact on markets and on investors. Preparing for future crises by strategically planning and diversifying your portfolio can help you continue to build wealth, even in uncertain times. Fortunately, there are some steps you can take to diversify and crisis-proof your investments, including using real estate diversification.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Consider Multifamily Real Estate Diversification</h2>



<p>While the stock market has seen significant changes in recent years due to inflation, interest rates, and financial uncertainty, the economic impact on multifamily real estate has been somewhat different. An ongoing housing shortage and changes in demographics across major city centers has kept demand for rental housing high, providing a potential hedge against inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Real estate market resilience has been due to the factors listed above, as well as the shift from in-office work to remote work, which has provided workers with the freedom to move to smaller secondary and tertiary markets. Rental income stability from multifamily real estate properties can provide investors with a consistent source of cash flow, even when stocks are not showing similar consistent performance. You don’t have to have millions of dollars to invest in multifamily real estate though, so it’s easier than you think to crisis-proof your portfolio. REITs and single-asset offerings, such as those from DiversyFund, let you add real estate to your portfolio without the need to purchase publicly traded stocks or to invest in a whole property on your own.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26274" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Think Long Term</h2>



<p>Investments designed to be held for the long-term may be ideal for those looking to crisis-proof their portfolios. Real estate diversification may not be as liquid as diversifying with stocks and bonds, but these investments let you build wealth over time without the volatility of traditional markets. Whether you purchase an apartment building to provide you with monthly income you can rely on for years to come or you invest in a REIT with the goal of improving and then selling a property, real estate gives you a unique way to diversify your portfolio.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, there are other long-term options that carry less risk than stock market investments. Certificates of Deposit (CDs) provide a guaranteed rate of return provided you hold on to the investment for the length of the term. CD ladders can be helpful for individuals looking to add stability to their portfolios and create dependable income over an extended period of time. CDs do come with trade-offs, such as illiquidity for the length of the investment term and potentially lower rates of return. Treasury bonds can also provide dependable rates of return and can be used to offset more risky investments you currently hold in your portfolio. While not FDIC-insured, they are backed by the full faith and credit of the government, providing some added peace of mind.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Assess Risk Tolerance</h2>



<p>If you are concerned about market volatility and diversifying your portfolio, assessing your risk tolerance might be a good idea. You’ll want to determine how much risk you’re comfortable with as well as how solid your financial situation is before you take on new investments. This means ensuring you have enough emergency funds to cover unexpected expenses without having to touch your current investments. Balancing your long-term goals with the liquidity of future investments may also be key. If you feel you might need access to your money sooner rather than later, having a mix of long-term and short-term investments might help you feel more comfortable and secure in your strategy. You don’t have to make this assessment on your own. Speaking to a financial advisor is a good first step before making any decisions, including on real estate diversification, and your advisor can help you perform a risk assessment and give you a better overall look at your current finances.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26275" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Do Your Research</h2>



<p>A financial advisor can be helpful in crisis-proofing your portfolio, but it’s always a good idea to stay on top of <a href="https://www.wsj.com/economy">current financial news</a> and world events. Having a better understanding of how the markets work and how world events can move markets can help inform your decisions and your discussions with your advisor. For example, following the housing shortage can provide insights into the benefits of investing in multifamily real estate. There are apps you can download to your phone or tablet that let you keep an eye on stock markets and financial news so you can stay informed of current events. Other apps let you track your investments, providing insight into how the news is impacting your portfolio.  DiversyFund’s easy-to-use app lets you monitor your real estate investment account so you always know where you stand. </p>



<p>World events can have a serious impact on the world of finance, but you don’t have to be subject to the whims of the markets or a victim of inflation. By diversifying your portfolio, you can hedge against instability and uncertainty while continuing to work towards your financial goals. Multifamily real estate can be an essential part of your wealth-building journey, and you can learn more about how DiversyFund can help using real estate diversification by clicking <a href="https://diversyfund.com/why-real-estate/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/10/06/crisis-proofing-your-portfolio-lessons-from-recent-global-events/">Crisis-Proofing Your Portfolio: Lessons from Recent Global Events</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diversification: The Yale Endowment Fund and You</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/26/diversification-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 22:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the dynamic world of investment, strategies employed by renowned institutions like Yale University&#8217;s Endowment Fund often serve as a beacon of wisdom for the everyday investor. One such strategy...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/26/diversification-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you/">Diversification: The Yale Endowment Fund and You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the dynamic world of investment, strategies employed by renowned institutions like <a href="https://investments.yale.edu/">Yale University&#8217;s Endowment Fund</a> often serve as a beacon of wisdom for the everyday investor. One such strategy that has gained significant attention in recent years is the allocation of funds to venture capital investments. This shift has provided meaningful insight into the opportunities needed to create a strong, successful portfolio for every investor.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Yale&#8217;s Venture Capital Strategy</strong></h2>



<p>Yale University&#8217;s Endowment Fund has long been admired for its consistent growth and impressive returns, largely attributed to its diversified investment approach. A noteworthy aspect of Yale&#8217;s portfolio is its growing allocation to venture capital investments. But why does one of the world&#8217;s most respected educational institutions choose to invest in startups and emerging companies?</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Diversification: </strong>Yale recognizes that a well-diversified portfolio is key to managing risk and achieving stable long-term returns. Venture capital investments offer a unique opportunity to diversify the portfolio by including assets with low correlation to traditional asset classes like stocks and bonds. This diversification can act as a cushion during market downturns, reducing the overall risk of the portfolio.</li>



<li><strong>Potential for High Returns:</strong> While venture capital investments come with higher risk, they also offer the potential for substantial returns. Startups that succeed can experience exponential growth, and their early-stage investors stand to benefit significantly. Yale&#8217;s willingness to take calculated risks in the venture capital space has paid off handsomely over the years.</li>



<li><strong>Access to Innovation:</strong> By investing in startups, Yale gains exposure to cutting-edge technologies and innovations. This not only has the potential to boost returns but also aligns with the institution&#8217;s mission to support and drive innovation. The insights gained from these investments can be invaluable.</li>



<li><strong>Long-Term Horizon</strong>: Yale&#8217;s endowment is designed to provide support for generations to come. As such, it has a long-term investment horizon. Venture capital investments, which often have longer gestation periods before delivering returns, align well with this objective.  </li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="http://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26266" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: https://investments.yale.edu/about-the-yio visited May 2023</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Everyday Investors Can Benefit</strong></h2>



<p>Now, let&#8217;s consider how the principles behind Yale&#8217;s venture capital strategy can be applied to the portfolios of everyday investors.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Diversification: </strong>Just like Yale, individual investors can benefit from diversifying their portfolios beyond traditional assets. Including a small allocation to alternative investments, such as real estate, private equity, or venture capital, can help spread risk and potentially enhance returns.</li>



<li><strong>Risk Management:</strong> While venture capital investments are known for their risk, individual investors can manage this risk by limiting their exposure. Diversifying within the venture capital space by investing in a venture capital fund or choosing startups carefully can help mitigate risk.</li>



<li><strong>Long-Term Perspective:</strong> Individual investors should also adopt a long-term perspective. Rather than seeking quick gains, focusing on the long-term potential of their investments can lead to better results. Patience is often rewarded in venture capital.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Stay Informed:</strong> Staying informed about emerging trends and technologies can help individual investors make informed decisions when considering venture capital investments.<a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/"> Following industry news</a>, attending conferences, or consulting with financial advisors can provide valuable insights.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26268" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/venture-capital-investments-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What it Means for Investors like You</strong></h2>



<p>DiversyFund offers a unique opportunity for everyday investors to access the world of alternative investments, including real estate and venture capital. DiversyFund&#8217;s approach to crowdfunding allows investors to pool their resources and invest in carefully selected projects. This aligns with the principle of diversification, much like Yale&#8217;s approach to venture capital.</p>



<p>Yale University&#8217;s Endowment Fund&#8217;s venture capital strategy offers valuable insights for everyday investors. By diversifying their portfolios, managing risk, adopting a long-term perspective, and staying informed, investors can apply these principles to their own financial goals. DiversyFund&#8217;s real estate investment platform serves as an accessible avenue for diversification, allowing individuals to benefit from these principles in practice.</p>



<p>Remember, successful investing is not about chasing quick gains but about building a well-rounded portfolio that stands the test of time. While we may not all have the resources of a prestigious institution like Yale, the principles of smart investing can be applied by anyone willing to take a thoughtful and strategic approach.</p>



<p>So, as you consider your investment strategy, take inspiration from Yale&#8217;s venture capital investments and explore how diversifying your portfolio through alternative investments, such as real estate and venture capital with <a href="https://diversyfund.com/">DiversyFund</a>, could play a role in your financial journey.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/26/diversification-the-yale-endowment-fund-and-you/">Diversification: The Yale Endowment Fund and You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Psychology of Investing &#8211; How to Avoid these Common Pitfalls</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/06/psychology-of-investing-how-to-avoid-these-common-pitfalls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 22:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[REITs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Psychology plays a key role in investing, and your biases can have an impact on how you choose to invest your money. Understanding investor emotional biases and strategies can help...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/06/psychology-of-investing-how-to-avoid-these-common-pitfalls/">Psychology of Investing &#8211; How to Avoid these Common Pitfalls</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Psychology plays a key role in investing, and your biases can have an impact on how you choose to invest your money. Understanding investor emotional biases and strategies can help you make more informed decisions when you’re ready to expand or diversify your portfolio. We’ll explore the psychology of investing and just how it can change the way you look at your financial strategy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding and Overcoming Investing Biases</h2>



<p>The field of <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/behavioralfinance.asp">behavioral finance</a> explores psychology and how it can affect the financial decisions of investors. Psychologists look at biases, including some you may have heard of in other contexts, such as confirmation bias, to better understand how these preconceptions can influence behaviors. By learning about biases, it can be easier to learn how to overcome them. We’ll cover a couple of key biases here to give you a better understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Confirmation Bias</h2>



<p>Confirmation bias occurs when people seek out information that aligns with existing beliefs. For investors, this might mean only seeking out certain types of companies or of investments that fit a preconceived narrative. For example, an investor might hear that a specific stock is going to outperform the rest due to a recent invention. He or she may subconsciously choose to only read articles and watch news segments that confirm the outlook for this stock, and then will finally invest only in this particular stock. The investor has not looked for any information that takes an objective look at the investment, resulting in a narrow focus and potential risk to his or her portfolio.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investors can overcome this type of bias by actively seeking out contrary opinions about different investments. By looking at both the pros and cons and weighing them equally, you can help avoid confirmation bias and make informed decisions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26250" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Loss Aversion</h2>



<p>Loss aversion is perhaps one of the easiest biases to understand, though it isn’t always easy to avoid. This concept covers the idea that some investors may be so afraid of losses that they avoid taking risks. This may result in holding onto losing investments for too long in the hopes of a bounce back or selling winning investments too soon to avoid a potential crash. In both situations, the individual makes an irrational or uninformed decision simply to avoid the stress of a potential loss.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Creating a diverse portfolio can help you avoid loss aversion. A diverse, balanced portfolio gives you the freedom to let winning investments continue to build or grow, as your other investments can act as a hedge should that winner start to lose ground. You can also work with a financial advisor to explore specific portfolio strategies, such as index investing or factor investing. Another option is to add specific types of long-term investments to your portfolio to create a targeted approach to stock market volatility. Real estate investments, for example, can help diversify your portfolio while offering protection against both volatility and inflation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Investor Emotional Bias Strategies</h2>



<p>While there are specific strategies to employ for different biases as outlined above, there are also some general strategies you can use to overcome a range of biases and investment decision emotional factors. You can employ the following strategies to take a more centered approach toward building wealth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Self Awareness</h2>



<p>The first step to overcoming biases is to recognize they exist. Take some time to analyze how you look at your current investments and how you approach picking new ones. Are you fully researching the different options available to you by weighing the pros and cons? Is there data to back up the decisions you make? Understanding how you come to your decisions can help you identify your biases so you can create a plan to avoid them.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Long-Term Goals</h2>



<p>Creating long-term goals may help you stay focused on the end result. Loss aversion and confirmation bias may narrow your view of investments so you’re only looking at short-term results. You may break down all your long-term goals, such as retirement, college savings, and even dream vacations so you’re always keeping your eye on the prize. Long-term investments, such as real estate, with less liquidity, can prevent you from making rash decisions based on your biases, and they can also help you create a more diverse portfolio to minimize risks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-03-1024x531.png" alt="Investor speaking with a financial advisor to help with making a decision. " class="wp-image-26251" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/psychology-of-investing-common-pitfalls-and-how-to-avoid-them-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Professional Advice</h2>



<p>Seeking professional advice makes it easier to overcome your biases. A financial advisor can help you identify different investments to add to your portfolio and provide you with risk assessments and analyses to better inform your financial moves. Your advisor acts as an objective third party who can potentially identify when biases are impacting your decision making. As always, we recommend discussing investments with a professional before making any decisions. DiversyFund is not a financial advisor and is not acting in such capacity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How the Psychology of Investing Impacts Investors Like You</h2>



<p>Everyone is susceptible to biases, whether we realize it or not. Taking the time to understand biases and how they impact financial decisions is the first step to helping ensure they don’t play a key role in your decision-making process. Whether you’re a first-time investor just learning the ropes or you’re an accredited investor looking to invest in a single-asset real estate offering, knowing more about how the psychology of investing works can give you more insight as you work to build wealth. To learn more about DiversyFund’s offerings for both accredited and non-accredited investors, click <a href="https://diversyfund.com/offerings/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/09/06/psychology-of-investing-how-to-avoid-these-common-pitfalls/">Psychology of Investing &#8211; How to Avoid these Common Pitfalls</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Managing Multifamily Properties: Trends and Innovations in Fintech</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/29/managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-in-fintech/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 03:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily real estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Technology has revolutionized almost every aspect of life, and that includes the world of multifamily real estate investing. An array of technological innovations have made it easier to create investment...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/29/managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-in-fintech/">Managing Multifamily Properties: Trends and Innovations in Fintech</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Technology has revolutionized almost every aspect of life, and that includes the world of multifamily real estate investing. An array of technological innovations have made it easier to create investment strategies, manage portfolios, invest in properties, and manage multifamily real estate assets, which are all part of the fintech space. With so many new tools available for investors, getting started in real estate has never been easier. Here’s a look at some of the major innovations and trends that are changing the way people like you invest in properties.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Revolutionary Fintech Investment Platforms</h2>



<p>Traditionally, investing in real estate portfolios, such as a REIT, required the help of a broker. These investments were not readily accessible to the general public, and everyday investors might not have even known how to invest in real estate without purchasing an entire property. Fintech investment platforms have expanded access to real estate investment opportunities through the use of mobile apps and websites, letting potential investors select properties and portfolios without the need for a personal broker. These platforms also allow individuals to invest smaller amounts to easily diversify their portfolios. For example, DiversyFund’s REITs allow investors to open and fund an account with as little as $500, giving them all the benefits of multifamily real estate investing previously enjoyed by the wealthy. Fintech also provides better access for accredited investors to make significant investments while managing their portfolios without the need for an intermediary.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26215" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI Real Estate Investment Strategies</h2>



<p>The use of AI in some industries has proven controversial, but the application of <a href="https://realtybiznews.com/the-power-of-artificial-intelligence-an-effective-tool-for-real-estate-investors/98777822/#:~:text=Machine%20learning%20algorithms%2C%20a%20subset,%2C%20sell%2C%20or%20hold%20properties.">AI-driven data analysis</a> can be beneficial for multifamily real estate investors. Artificial intelligence can analyze market trends, including property values, vacancy rates, rent rates, and other key metrics to help investors predict the potential success of a property. The technology can also be used to identify emerging markets based on demographics, job markets, and social data. While it might take an individual a considerable amount of time to research all this data, AI can perform the same tasks quickly to help users craft real estate investment strategies and portfolio management strategies for individual markets and submarkets. Of course, any data acquired from artificial intelligence still needs a human touch to identify any potential errors and to make informed decisions based on the provided information.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trends and Innovations in PropTech</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesbusinesscouncil/2022/05/11/the-impact-of-proptech-today-and-where-the-industry-is-heading/?sh=3510b2917860">PropTech</a>, or property technology, is used in every aspect of real estate. You see it in action whenever you look for a new home using real estate websites, and it’s also used by real estate agents, banks, and underwriters to initiate and complete real estate transactions. Proptech is an umbrella term similar to fintech, but its impact on multifamily real estate investment can’t be ignored. Property managers use this technology to keep track of rents, vacancy rates, and other metrics to help ensure assets run smoothly and maintain profitability for investors. Every step of the real estate purchase and management processes has been improved through the use of PropTech.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26216" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/the-role-of-technology-in-managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Property Management and Solutions for Tenants</h2>



<p>Of course, no multifamily real estate investment can be profitable without its tenants, and tech trends for renters have helped improve their quality of living and satisfaction with their rental units. Property management dashboards allow tenants to pay rent and request maintenance online, making it easier for them to access the services they need. Smart home technologies, such as keyless entry doors, eliminate the need to call maintenance for lost or stolen keys, provide temporary access codes to guests, and help increase the feeling of safety on a property. Renter engagement software programs and apps used by property management companies provide information about upcoming repairs, community events, and other important information, and they also help automate the process of renewing leases. Access to these benefits and services were limited before technology trends began playing such an integral role in the multifamily real estate industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fintech and PropTech have made lasting marks on real estate, and these technologies continue to benefit both investors and renters. Automated data services, <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/">simple investment platforms</a>, streamlined property management services, and AI-driven investment strategies have made it easier than ever for everyone to become an informed real estate investor. Of course, you should always consult with an expert to weigh your options and determine your individual risk level before making any financial decisions. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/29/managing-multifamily-properties-trends-and-innovations-in-fintech/">Managing Multifamily Properties: Trends and Innovations in Fintech</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Understanding the Power of Crowdfunding in Real Estate Investing</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/08/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Fintech is changing the way people invest their money, and real estate crowdfunding might be one of the best examples of how tech has made investing more accessible to all....</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/08/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing/">Understanding the Power of Crowdfunding in Real Estate Investing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Fintech is changing the way people invest their money, and real estate crowdfunding might be one of the best examples of how tech has made investing more accessible to all. From beginners to experienced accredited investors, multifamily real estate crowdfunding has something for everyone. Read on to find out more about the power of crowdfunding and how it can help diversify your portfolio.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate Crowdfunding Platforms</h2>



<p>Real estate crowdfunding platforms take the guesswork out of investing. Easy-to-use dashboards, real-time investment performance stats, and automatic investment options are just some of the features that make it simple for investors to fund and manage their accounts. Some real estate crowdfunding platforms let you choose between different portfolios of multifamily real estate properties, while others let you select a single property to invest your money.<br><br>These unique platforms can be accessed by both traditional websites and mobile apps, so you can track your investment progress no matter where you are. Companies like <a href="https://diversyfund.com/lp/venture-investment-regd/">DiversyFund</a> even let you review information and pictures of different properties available for investment, so you can truly see where your money is going when you fund your account.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26184" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Venture Investments</h2>



<p>While crowdfunding does provide opportunities to invest in individual properties or groups of properties, venture investments let you invest in the real estate company itself. Groups of investors can pool their money together to give startups their initial funding or additional rounds of funding to support new projects or initiatives. The <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/j/jumpstart-our-business-startups-act-jobs.asp#:~:text=The%20JOBS%20Act%20allows%20retail,small%20investors%20pooling%20their%20resources.">JOBS Act of 2012</a> changed some of the rules on crowdfunding, making it easier for businesses to raise capital and for investors to build wealth with fewer SEC regulations getting in the way. As a side note, investors in any venture offering should consult a financial advisor to assess the risk before investing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">REITs (Real Estate Investment Trusts)</h2>



<p>While Real Estate Investment Trusts, or REITs, have been around for years, advances in fintech and the platforms used for crowdfunding real estate have also had a huge impact on REITs. Individual non-accredited investors can now easily put their money into a portfolio and own shares of real estate properties throughout the country instead of simply purchasing stock in REIT companies. Low investment minimums mean individuals can invest in a REIT with as little as $500, which can be set up as a one-time investment or a recurring transaction. DiversyFund offers a convenient Auto Invest option, which lets you fund your account every month and grow your investment over time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Real Estate Crowdfunding for Accredited Investors</h2>



<p>The JOBS Act of 2012 also made it easier for accredited investors to put their money into single-asset offerings. This means investors meeting certain minimum wealth requirements can pool money with others to fund individual real estate offerings. Essentially, you can help fund a large multifamily real estate development without being the sole investor and assuming all of the risk. Accredited investors may prefer this option, as it gives them more freedom to select properties based on performance potential and location, and it also lets them diversify their real estate holdings by investing in multiple ventures.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Pros and Cons of Crowdfunding Multifamily Real Estate</h2>



<p>As with any type of investment, there are benefits and drawbacks associated with crowdfunding multifamily real estate. DiversyFund offers options for venture investments, REITs, and single-asset offerings for accredited investors, so you can select the option and investment minimum that meets your financial goals and risk tolerance. As you begin to think about how to start your wealth-building journey, it’s a good idea to look at both the pros and cons before making a decision. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26183" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><br>Fintech has truly democratized the multifamily real estate market, making it easy for everyone to build wealth and take control of their financial future. Mobile apps let you literally carry your portfolio wherever you go, giving you access to performance data and making it easy to invest in additional properties, capital raises, or investment trusts with just a few swipes of your finger.</p>



<p><br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/07/08/understanding-the-power-of-crowdfunding-in-real-estate-investing/">Understanding the Power of Crowdfunding in Real Estate Investing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlocking the Potential: Multifamily vs. Single-Family Rentals</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/23/multifamily-rentals-vs-single-family/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 22:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily rentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[single family rentals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investing in real estate can be an exciting proposition, but you’ll need to decide if you want to invest in single-family homes or multifamily rentals. Both options have benefits and...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/23/multifamily-rentals-vs-single-family/">Unlocking the Potential: Multifamily vs. Single-Family Rentals</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investing in real estate can be an exciting proposition, but you’ll need to decide if you want to invest in single-family homes or multifamily rentals. Both options have benefits and drawbacks, so taking a closer look at each option can help you make the choice that makes the most sense for your portfolio and your risk comfort level.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cash Flow Potential</h2>



<p>Whether you invest in a single-family home or a multifamily rentals, the goal of the investment should be to generate cash flow. For a single-family home, your potential cash flow is limited to just one unit. This means you can only generate income from one source every month, and tenant turnover may mean you’re left without cash flow for a number of months. There are ways to maximize cash flow on a single family home, to an extent, by renting the property out as a short-term vacation property instead of to a long-term lessee. However, using the home as a vacation rental may be risky, as you may not be able to book short-term tenants for every night of the month. </p>



<p>With multifamily real estate, your cash flow is generated across multiple units. Even with a small apartment building, your monthly income can be significantly higher than with a single-family home. Having several units also means you can mitigate the risk of losing income; should a single unit become vacant, you still have revenue generating from the others in the building or complex. <br>For comparison, average rental rates for single-family detached homes hit <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2023/05/07/single-family-homes-rent-increase/70185035007/">$2,330</a> per month in 2023. Average apartment rent rates sit at about <a href="https://www.rentcafe.com/average-rent-market-trends/us/">$1,700</a>. While the first number may seem more impressive, remember that the second would be multiplied by the number of apartments in the building or complex. Cash flow opportunities are greater with multifamily real estate.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26169" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Passive Income</h2>



<p>Investors in both multifamily rentals and single-family homes seek to make passive income off their investments. Passive income is income you make outside of a regular job and that does not require a significant amount of labor. Investing in a single house may seem like an easy way to boost your monthly income, but some may find it’s not quite so simple. Purchasing a house to rent out puts you in the role of landlord, and that means handling renovations and repairs, collecting rents, seeking out new tenants if your current ones decide to leave, and handling all other aspects of the property. Investors in single-family homes may not be able to afford to hire a property management company, which means all the work falls on them. It’s not so passive after all. </p>



<p>A multifamily real estate asset, on the other hand, can be a true source of passive income. The potential cash flow across multiple units or multiple buildings means you can absorb the cost of hiring a property management company. You can avoid stepping into the role of landlord while still reaping the benefits of your real estate investment. The property managers handle all aspects of the business, so you can decide how much you want to be involved, if at all.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Portfolio Growth and Long-Term Appreciation</h2>



<p>Both single-family homes and multifamily properties have the potential for long-term appreciation. A home purchased in the right neighborhood at the right time can command higher rents and grow in value, but this growth may be limited. With just one asset in your portfolio, you may find only moderate increases. Another challenge with investing in single-family homes is the limited opportunity for building your portfolio. You’ll need to keep adding homes to grow and diversify your portfolio, which can be a challenge for average investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Multifamily real estate holds a greater opportunity for both long-term appreciation and portfolio growth. Apartment buildings purchased in secondary or tertiary markets can benefit from the growing populations and job markets in their areas, with demand for housing commanding higher rents across the board. Multiplying the rent market rate across the number of units may yield considerable growth, and the overall value of the investment can appreciate in value as the city grows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investing in several multifamily assets to build a portfolio may seem daunting, but there are many investment vehicles available that let you put your money into several properties or groups of properties. For example, a REIT lets you pool your money with other investors to purchase shares in a portfolio of properties. These assets can be limited to a specific geographical region or they can be spread out across the country to help mitigate risk. <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/what-does-it-take-to-be-accredited/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-6-23">Accredited investors</a> can also take advantage of single-asset offerings, like those offered by DiversyFund. A single-asset offering pools the money from a smaller group of investors to purchase, manage, and eventually sell one multifamily real estate asset. You don’t have to have millions of dollars in the bank to invest in large-scale real estate properties, so you can have all the advantages of multifamily real estate investing while sharing the potential risks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="http://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26165" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/multifamily-real-estate-vs-single-family-real-estate-which-is-better-for-investors-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>Finding the right balance for your investment portfolio means crafting an investment strategy that fits your needs and your risk tolerance level. While investing in a single-family home may be a good option for some people, you may find the benefits of investing in multifamily rentals meet your financial goals better. With opportunities for cash flow, passive income, and long-term appreciation, multifamily rental properties can make a smart addition to your portfolio. If you’re ready to begin building long-term wealth, <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/?utm_source=inbound-content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-6-23">click here</a> to learn more about how DiversyFund’s offerings can help you.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/23/multifamily-rentals-vs-single-family/">Unlocking the Potential: Multifamily vs. Single-Family Rentals</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Books: Investing for Success</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/02/beyond-books-investing-for-success/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investing101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passive Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[value investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investors of all experience levels are always looking for great advice on how to build wealth, but most advice from books and blogs can be boiled down to the same...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/02/beyond-books-investing-for-success/">Beyond Books: Investing for Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investors of all experience levels are always looking for great advice on how to build wealth, but most advice from books and blogs can be boiled down to the same bits of basic information. Some investors may be left wondering why they haven’t struck it rich after following all the expert opinions. Even more walk away from the bookshelf still wondering how to become a real estate investor – or how to be successful at it. However, there are some key points that might get missed in all the research and casual reading investors do. So just what does it take to become a successful investor?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Get Started</h2>



<p>The best, most simple piece of advice for investors is to get started with investing. Reading all the books won’t help if you haven’t put your money in any investment opportunities. Getting started can be as simple as learning about different types of investment accounts and selecting the ones that make the most sense to you. Some basic types of investment accounts for beginners to consider include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Individual stocks and bonds</li>



<li>Mutual funds</li>



<li>Certificates of Deposit</li>



<li>REITs</li>
</ul>



<p>If you’re unsure about where to start, a financial advisor can help you craft a plan that aligns with your financial goals. The most important step to securing your financial future is to begin planning for it as soon as possible. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26137" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Consider Value Investing</h2>



<p>When selecting where to put your money, it’s important to look for value. Another way of describing this principle is <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/v/valueinvesting.asp">value investing</a>. With this strategy, investors look for stocks or other assets they believe are trading below their actual value. By purchasing shares at a lower price, investors can help maximize their profits. The shares become profitable as other investors begin to realize the value of the company and begin investing as well, driving the price higher than what you paid for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While this idea is often associated with stocks, it is also applicable to other types of investing. For example, a multifamily real estate property with a history of underperforming can provide you with an opportunity to invest at a discount and begin growing wealth by improving the asset and increasing cash flow. Emerging markets are often home to undervalued real estate assets, as the true potential of the regions they cover have not been fully realized yet. Properties can be purchased for less than they’re worth, providing potential for considerable growth moving forward. Value investing can be a long-term strategy, so it requires patience and the willingness to do plenty of research before making any money moves.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Diversify Your Portfolio</h2>



<p>You’ve probably heard advice about diversifying your portfolio before, but what does that actually mean? Simply put, it means not to put all your eggs in one basket. Relying only on one investment opportunity can lead to potential disaster for your finances. For example, if you have all your money in a single stock, you can lose everything if the company goes under. Creating a diverse portfolio means investing in several different types of accounts or assets to hedge against losses, inflation, and market volatility. Balancing your portfolio might mean creating a CD ladder to create consistent dependable cash flow to offset potential losses in the stock market. You can invest in real estate, which lets you hedge against inflation while helping build long-term wealth. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Practice Patience</h2>



<p>One reason investors can be easily frustrated by financial advice is the lack of instant results. Investing in anything, whether it’s real estate or the stock market, is not a get-rich-quick scheme. It requires patience and the ability to ride out periods of market volatility. A good rule of thumb for investing is to only invest what you can afford to lose. While this may mean only investing a small amount of money for potentially lower returns, it can also help prevent losses you can’t absorb. Looking at investing as a long-term commitment instead of expecting instant results can help you reframe the way you look at your money and reach your financial goals.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26138" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/beyond-books-investing-for-success-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Learn How to Become a Real Estate Investor</h2>



<p>As mentioned above, <a href="https://diversyfund.com/why-real-estate/?utm_source=organic&amp;utm_medium=inbound-content&amp;campaign_name=blog-post&amp;term=6-2">investing in real estate</a> can help you diversify your portfolio and weather potential storms in the markets. REITs and single-asset real estate offerings let you pool your money with other investors to purchase properties that are managed for you. This form of passive investing lets you build your wealth without having to take on the role of a landlord. You can select the funds you want to invest in, and you can control how much money you invest at any given time. For example, DiversyFund’s REITs let you invest with just $500, so you don’t have to have tens or hundreds of thousands of dollars on hand. </p>



<p>The key to becoming a successful investor isn’t hidden in the pages of a book. Simply doing the research, being patient, and coming up with a plan to create a diverse portfolio can make all the difference. Go into every investment with realistic expectations and don’t be afraid to talk to a financial advisor for guidance.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/06/02/beyond-books-investing-for-success/">Beyond Books: Investing for Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Due Diligence Difference: Elevating Multifamily Investing Strategies</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/26/elevating-multifamily-investing-strategies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 22:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[due diligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal concerns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property inspections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investing in multifamily real estate properties can be a great way to diversify your portfolio, but performing due diligence is essential when determining an asset’s viability as an investment. Due...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/26/elevating-multifamily-investing-strategies/">The Due Diligence Difference: Elevating Multifamily Investing Strategies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investing in multifamily real estate properties can be a great way to diversify your portfolio, but performing due diligence is essential when determining an asset’s viability as an investment. Due diligence requires the investor to look at several aspects of a property before making a purchase decision, and we’ll take a closer look at each of those aspects. With the right understanding of how to perform due diligence, you can prepare for your entry into the multifamily real estate investment world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding Due Diligence</h2>



<p>At its core, due diligence is the process investors go through to help ensure they’ve met all the legal requirements for making a purchase and to determine if they should move forward with that purchase. The information gathered can reveal important information, such as major repair needs uncovered during the inspection to potential tax liabilities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reviewing Financial Statements</h2>



<p>You’ll want to know how well a multifamily real estate property has performed in the past before deciding to invest. This means reviewing financial statements to help determine the current and potential future cash flow for the asset. You can ask to review profit and loss statements (P&amp;L statements) and T-12 report (Trailing Twelve Months Report). These reports review operating expenses and income for a property, breaking everything down into easy-to-read line items.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The P&amp;L reports should go back several years to give you a better look at the property’s financial strength over time. The T-12 report provides essentially the same information as a P&amp;L, but it lets you look for any changes in the asset’s performance within the last year. While a multifamily asset might have a strong history of profits, there may have been changes in recent months indicating potential red flags. By looking at both documents, you can get a better feel for the way the property will perform for you. Additionally, you can ask to see vacancy reports and records of property tax payments to further analyze the property’s cash flow and potential liabilities.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26131" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Property Inspections</h2>



<p>Just as with purchasing a home for personal use, an inspection is essential for purchasing a multifamily real estate asset. The inspection should look at the roof, basement/foundation, plumbing, electrical, and structural makeup of the building or buildings you’re looking to purchase. While some repairs are likely needed for any property, big-ticket fixes such as a new roof or bringing electrical wiring up to code may lead you to decide against making a purchase. You can use the information in the report to estimate the cost of necessary repairs and take them into account before investing. Depending on market conditions, you may be able to negotiate with the owners to have some repairs done for you or to lower the purchase price based on the need for repairs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Legal Review and Tax Review</h2>



<p>Having a lawyer and accountant on your team can help you further vet a property. The lawyer will be able to look at the property’s current leases to ensure compliance with local laws and regulations, and he or she can also examine the property for any potential liens, easements, or competing legal claims you might need to contend with. Your lawyer should also look at any past litigation associated with the property and review zoning information to ensure the property is compliant with local regulations regarding its intended use. A <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/mortgages-real-estate/08/real-estate-attorney.asp">full legal review</a> may prevent costly surprises after the property has been purchased. </p>



<p>Similarly, your accountant can also identify potential financial liabilities with an asset before you invest. Examining tax certificates and ensuring past payment of property taxes can prevent you from taking on additional debt and headaches immediately after purchase. Your accountant may also review the financial documents you’ve gathered on the property to help you better understand all the information, such as individual line items in the P&amp;L statement and how they might impact the bottom line.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26132" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/img-the-importance-of-due-diligence-in-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Comparative Property Analysis</h2>



<p>If you’ve ever purchased a new home, you’ve likely heard your real estate agent talk about comps. The concept behind a comparative property analysis for multifamily real estate is similar to the comps you’re familiar with from your home purchase. The comparative property analysis, also known as a <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/competitive-market-analysis-what-exactly-is-it/?utm_source=inbound%20content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-5-26">comparative market analysis</a> or CMA, is an estimate of a property’s price based on certain market factors. For multifamily real estate assets, these factors might include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Location</li>



<li>Rental rates</li>



<li>Occupancy rates</li>



<li>Property amenities&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Commercial real estate agents may have comparative property analysis reports available for review, but you can also create your own estimate based on other similar properties in the area. It’s important to remember that the analysis is not an appraisal; it is an estimated value. An appraisal should still be performed for any property you are interested in investing in, as part of the due diligence process, and you may find the appraised value can be higher or lower than the comparative property analysis indicates.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What it Means for Investors Like You</h2>



<p>If due diligence sounds like a lot of work, that’s because it is. You have to examine a property from many different angles, including its financial history, tax history, and potential legal liabilities. The process can be time-consuming if you do it all on your own, but it’s essential for making an informed investment decision. Fortunately, you don’t have to do it all. DiversyFund offers a host of investment options for individuals of all experience levels, and we carefully vet each property before offering it as an option for your portfolio. All the steps of the due diligence process <a href="https://diversyfund.com/about/?utm_source=inbound%20content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-5-26">are taken care</a> of for you, so you can invest with confidence and without having to do all the legwork yourself.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/26/elevating-multifamily-investing-strategies/">The Due Diligence Difference: Elevating Multifamily Investing Strategies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mastering Multifamily: The Impact of Interest Rates on Real Estate Investments</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/20/mastering-multifamily-the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-real-estate-investments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interest rates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multifamily investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate terms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When evaluating whether to invest in multifamily real estate, it’s important to take current interest rates into account. The impact of interest rates can be reflected in the rate of...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/20/mastering-multifamily-the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-real-estate-investments/">Mastering Multifamily: The Impact of Interest Rates on Real Estate Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When evaluating whether to invest in multifamily real estate, it’s important to take current interest rates into account. The impact of interest rates can be reflected in the rate of return for a property and property values. Investors may also use interest rates to inform their overall investment strategy. Taking a moment to better understand how rates work and how they impact multifamily real estate investments can help you better diversify your portfolio.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Investment Returns</h2>



<p>Interest rates essentially dictate the cost of borrowing money, so real estate investments that require financing can be impacted by changes in current rates. As the cost of borrowing increases, investment returns will be lower. During times of lower interest, returns may be higher because of the reduced cost of borrowing money. This is reflected in the <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/mortgages-real-estate/08/interest-rates-affect-property-values.asp#:~:text=When%20the%20required%20returns%20on,fall%2C%20real%20estate%20prices%20increase.">NOI (Net Operating Income)</a> of an investment. Simply put, borrowing money to invest in multifamily real estate can result in better investment returns when interest rates remain low.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26117" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Property Valuation</h2>



<p>When the potential for cash flow in a property decreases, the overall value of the property itself can also decrease. When interest rates are high, property valuations may be lower. Lower valuations can make it more difficult to sell a property, leaving investors holding onto an asset for potentially longer than planned. As interest rates fall, a property’s valuation can go up. Investors use lower interest rates as an indicator that it might be time to sell an asset for more profit.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Fixed Vs. Variable Interest Rates</h2>



<p>When financing a multifamily real estate asset, investors have <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-is-the-difference-between-fixed-and-variable-rate-auto-financing-en-757/">two options</a>. They can opt for a fixed interest rate, which provides stability over the life of the investment. However, they can also choose a variable interest rate. Fixed rates are often less risky, but variable interest rates can prove to be smart in some situations.</p>



<p>A fixed rate means the same interest rate is paid throughout the life of the real estate loan, but the cost of borrowing may be higher. With a variable rate, financing is provided at a lower rate that is subject to change. Financing a property when interest rates can be smart for a short-term loan, as there is less risk of the cost increasing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Yield Spread</h2>



<p>The concept of a yield spread is a bit complex, but it essentially refers to the difference between the cap rate of a property and the interest rate on it. You may also hear this metric referred to as the cap rate spread or the yield cap rate spread. The cap rate is the expected rate of return, while the interest rate refers to the cost of borrowing money for the investment asset. A higher spread indicates the multifamily property is generating a higher rate of return.&nbsp;Of course, this is a simplification of the equation, as it is typically measured next to the current interest rate of the federal 10-year treasury note. The most important thing to understand about <a href="https://www.jpmorgan.com/commercial-banking/insights/cap-rates-explained">cap rates and yield spread</a> in relation to interest rates is that lower interest rates typically result in lower spread, while higher interest rates may lead to higher spreads.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26118" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Inflation</h2>



<p>The impact of inflation on interest rates and multifamily real estate investing is particularly interesting. Higher interest rates can make it more expensive to borrow money for investing, but they can also make it more difficult for first-time homebuyers to borrow as well. In the current economic climate, a shortage of available houses for sale combined with higher interest rates may lead to more people deciding to rent instead of making a home purchase. This may actually be a benefit for multifamily real estate investing.</p>



<p>However, it’s important to consider other factors. Inflation can lead to an increase in the cost of construction materials, which provides a challenge to builders of new multifamily housing complexes. Lower supply drives up the prices of purchasing property, leading to potentially lower returns for investors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Interest Rates Impact Your Multifamily Investment Strategy</h2>



<p>It’s impossible to judge the multifamily real estate market solely based on current interest rates. Many other factors need to be taken into account when choosing an investment property and when deciding to sell an asset. Lower interest rates can result in lower costs of borrowing and greater borrowing power, while higher rates may mean higher rents and greater returns. It’s important to evaluate each situation on its own merits by taking your financial goals and risk tolerance into account. As always, be sure to consult with your financial advisor before making any money moves.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-04-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26119" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-04-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-04-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-04-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-04-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-multifamily-real-estate-investing-04.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>DiversyFund offers REITs and single-asset multifamily real estate investment options for both accredited and non-accredited investors, and we carefully evaluate each property, as well as interest rates, market volatility, and other factors, all so <a href="https://diversyfund.com/how-it-works/?utm_source=inbound%20content%20&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog-post-5-19">you don’t have to</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/05/20/mastering-multifamily-the-impact-of-interest-rates-on-real-estate-investments/">Mastering Multifamily: The Impact of Interest Rates on Real Estate Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth Trends: Emerging Real Estate Markets</title>
		<link>https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/28/growth-trends-emerging-real-estate-markets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Tomicic]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 22:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emerging markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tertiary markets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://diversyfund.com/?p=26076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Emerging real estate markets provide investors with plenty of potential for growth, but understanding how to identify these markets is key. Fortunately, there are several factors investors can use to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/28/growth-trends-emerging-real-estate-markets/">Growth Trends: Emerging Real Estate Markets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Emerging real estate markets provide investors with plenty of potential for growth, but understanding how to identify these markets is key. Fortunately, there are several factors investors can use to determine which areas are likely to show growth potential in the future. We’ll take a closer look at each of these factors and how they contribute to an emerging market’s possible future success.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are Emerging Real Estate Markets?</h2>



<p>An <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/understanding-secondary-and-tertiary-emerging-markets-in-real-estate/#:~:text=Satellite%20communities%20and%20exurban%20areas,to%20invest%20in%20real%20estate.">emerging real estate market</a> is typically considered to be a market with a population of less than 1 million people, although this can depend on the area and how close it is to another major metropolitan area. Emerging markets are also sometimes referred to as tertiary markets, and they demonstrate potential for growth in both development and investment revenue. Fort Worth, Texas fits into this category, so we’ll use it as a case study to demonstrate how investors can identify emerging markets with growth potential.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shifts in Demographics</h2>



<p>Changes in the demographics of an area can be a key indicator of an area’s readiness for growth. Influxes of young families, working professionals, or retirees looking for desirable housing can have a positive impact on the local real estate market. They can drive demand for new apartments and may even be able to afford higher rents, and increases in population may also lead to job creation to help the local economy grow even more.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-02-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26078" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-02-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-02-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-02-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-02-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-02.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Fort Worth has shown consistent population growth from 2018-2022, gaining nearly <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2022/05/population-shifts-in-cities-and-towns-one-year-into-pandemic.html">30,000</a> new citizens, and the greater Dallas Fort-Worth area has also seen an influx of new faces. In fact, Fort Worth touts itself as the <a href="https://itbeginsinfortworth.com/incentives/?gclid=CjwKCAjw9J2iBhBPEiwAErwpecCebo-ArSSxO9I7kSKTeJtPcWKh9DooqUdY-DbGBvGRKaqHJkLA-xoCNSkQAvD_BwE">sixth-fastest growing city</a> in the country. With its increase in new residents, Fort Worth shows promise for real estate investors looking to branch out into different markets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Economic Indicators for Emerging Real Estate Markets</h2>



<p>Of course, shifts in population are not the only indicators of an area’s growth potential. Economic indicators, such as unemployment rates and job growth are also key when examining emerging real estate markets. Low unemployment rates, coupled with new businesses and jobs moving to the area, can help support population growth in an emerging market.&nbsp;<br>For Fort Worth, along with the greater Dallas-Fort Worth area, the job market shows strength and promise. The <a href="https://www.bls.gov/regions/southwest/news-release/areaemployment_dallasfortworth.htm">Bureau of Labor Statistics</a> reports a gain of over 46,000 jobs in the professional and business services sectors, along with over 30,000 jobs in the trades and another 30,000 in education and healthcare sectors. These statistics point to a robust job market, which can make the region desirable for new residents and can also support higher rents for those looking to move to the area.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Infrastructure Investments</h2>



<p>Emerging markets must invest in improved infrastructure to support the influx of new residents and new businesses flocking to the area. Without new infrastructure supports, communities in emerging markets can’t support growth over time. Investors should look for areas with governments that understand the demographic shifts that are impacting the local economy and can react appropriately to help foster a healthy economy and real estate market.&nbsp;<br>The government of <a href="https://www.fortworthtexas.gov/projects">Fort Worth</a> has responded to its population growth and the needs of residents by investing in its infrastructure. Road construction to improve traffic, community center revitalization, and sewage/storm drain improvements are all listed among the city’s planned capital improvements.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="531" src="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-03-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-26080" srcset="https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-03-1024x531.png 1024w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-03-300x156.png 300w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-03-768x399.png 768w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-03-1536x797.png 1536w, https://diversyfund.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/identifying-emerging-real-estate-markets-with-growth-potential-03.png 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Local Incentives to Invest</h2>



<p>In addition to spending money on improving infrastructure, emerging markets that are most appealing to investors also support favorable investment conditions. This might mean tax breaks for businesses looking to relocate to the area, and it can also include lower property taxes or less stringent regulations on property development.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fort Worth offers <a href="https://itbeginsinfortworth.com/incentives/local-programs/">tax incentives and loans</a> for certain business industries, such as transportation, oil and gas, warehousing, manufacturing, healthcare, and tourism. The goal of these incentives is to bring new businesses to the area to support the improvement of the city. The local government considers itself to be pro-business, which can be a great sign for commercial investors and those looking to invest in real estate in the area.&nbsp;<br>Not all smaller cities are considered to be emerging markets. Having a population of under 1 million is just one piece of the puzzle. Increases in population growth, a robust local economy, ongoing infrastructure improvements, and favorable investment conditions are all essential for an emerging market’s potential success. DiversyFund’s team of real estate experts conducts <a href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/market-overview-dallas-fort-worth-metroplex/?utm_source=inbound%20content&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;campaign_name=blog%20post-4-28">thorough research</a> on potential markets before diving deeper into specific assets.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com/blog/2023/04/28/growth-trends-emerging-real-estate-markets/">Growth Trends: Emerging Real Estate Markets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://diversyfund.com">DiversyFund</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
